<body>###PAGE###1###
:!
f

B
&
-t—




#


4»
S?

VOL. VII.
SIIAWVILLE, COUNTY OF PONTIAC, QUE., JAN. 16, 1690.
No. 31.

?
LOCAL NEWS
Another heavy fall of enuw on <date>Saturday</date> Tho market prices remain practically snco people to refuso to unite thernsalvee ollowed by rain on <date>Monday</date>.	the same as last week.	with workers in that field, for any of the
The Mercury went down to 20 3 below On <date>Wednesday</date> of last week, Mr. Jas.	-?-- ,	reasons which I will proceed to give.
zero on <date>Thursday</date> night.	B. Thomson, barrister, Arnprior, young- Ontario I'-Sincii CJoUogO, Bo.*CVillO, One has objections to secret societies.
iir ( heap Headstone# and Monuments at est son of Sheriff Thompson, of Peril»,	Out*	i While there may be a good deal said upon
wi	...»k. ssrt* slhs:fzr.x
teasss? hzsi^~r; bçêsgâs
ElSraisS Stes’SS —«sss £=•-“
“—""............-	=â.	=issSsiii
SS^àMcd; h''lid.n .re o,er; once mure .he bar, cu.mg the „plo.,on.	We know there are wolves in sheep'.
pants. The nsm**s of Miss Poupore, Miss Putse "cr *houlder to the a heel and is	I __	fimrx„ w„Tit t	i«.u	eaiA	clothing in every branch and department
Kennedy and MIm Lmdon might be mention- teaching the young ideas how to shout.	QJOOC^	uOTOmmLni	*.tu0.	nf an,j w|HMl tho object of a society is
W.H.KLOCK M.O.,	....—- "rf S*fi3 K5	0—«.ou-nd
£%*r"¦	-fci;=rzs-'; êSkSS
3SSSSf8s35Si$S1	fe | "sses*» »*,,,...	$ Xiï ï"::Æ. SH=SS«“
them.	I	of	tho family. The d read disease uipht he- <vl to her school	ritzj>atriok	bought nearly	.>00	tinier	We know too well, that often Temperance
rid earned the rvmamderawny.	Mi». Maggie" Thomson it at home.	<* P'j'® at	price, ranging	from	«76	kSKeitamVf,'ju»V[h2io‘l2?riTw"«hn Sri"
Roby who ha. been absent under the Itn per mile. Walter Rom bought that ftan When this Division wa. being care of Dr. W. H Klnck, Ottawa, i, SO mile, at from «130 to «166. «nn. I ^nVn.e^'i““ .o0 tt'il much improved. The Dr. has made a dames Mchh&ne purchased, with H. Hog- «tarde. If n doom I will then Join.” I do not.
~~“ srr es®5Bhsss
JSr “¦	*-¦“ “ - - %% 5 SL>; ~ A Ssr ......................
sw-Arst.'ws rds rs wiiiteiHSSr
prize offered for the young lady who »"*¦ per acre. . now and then. u:»U, ala» ! loo often, U U
take, control st the station? Sailors I In the Uke 8t John district H. .T. Bee | ntherwlae. hat. J hear.	msr bought 72 miles at $17.10 at $1 and
The store keepers are doing a large | *9** #9 business here.
January 11th
the equity
1.
1
1

A WEEKLY JOURNAL
Ë
¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦!Mis» Aile* Porteou*, eldest daughter
Specially Devoted to Local Interests, 1,0

1
fUBLIhllED AT Hit A W VIL1.K

EVERY THURSDAY


u
Il Y


M.
vows
Subscription SI s Year in Advance
Advertising rates made known on applloa
lion. Correspondence solicited from all parts of the County.
JOB PRINTING A SPECIALTY. 31
Professional, Hotel and Business Cards.
are


on
t
HENRY AYLEN.LLM
/
BARRISTER AC., AO
•t
ATLXER
QUE.
*. TATLOR CLAVS01T,	.	-,	.	.	4k _
TTAILIKPOF SUPERIOR COURT Collec. Jsmee M(X,1re’ (ur Ammore, as the H i tor for Quehpf* mii«I Ontario. Offlr* No. tawa papers have it) of Aldfleld, and P R4, Main Street, Hull, P. 4.	30-ly of Halverson post office, has rot him-
_	---- self into trouble by having a whiakev still
. JH. HOBBS,	on his premises, lie was arrested
LICENSED AUCTIONEER, taken to Hull last week, where on <date>Wednesday</date> he was fined $100 and sentenced
of theeounîy ^ 811	In all parts to one month's imprisonment.
Lady Stanley’s suggestion of an tute for trained nurses for Ottawa is now
and
nmlstencieM, the

ROBT.8. McNEIL,	Il I I . P P J
¥>AILIFFOFTHERUPKR10R COURT for I almost certain to take practical shape,
k 1%^%
- ----- — ¦ — —	--— proposed institute has for its endorsers a
nun'^r	citizen, .mon* wh".*
Uoe psid to gnests. First Class Tables.	are Sheriff Sweet land, Mr. Travers Lewis,
nsKBSSsS K	u1.
•om modal ion ; commodious sample rooms ; Burn, and a number of leading philan-Wo. 1 llqnor. In the b»r._ | thropio Udiee.
One man has not the moral courage to re fu»e. In It not a wonder that inch men ever get through life without making of It a perfect failure? That they sometime» do must be owing to the goodness and Divine merry of " One who remembers we are but dust " We are told by some that hotels bring eus.	...	, tom to the businessmen, and that they make
The election of councillors for this Vll thing* lively In the place, (too lively some-
lage on <date>Monday</date> /Oioniiiig last, passed off I times ) Do those men ever tske it loo con_____________________	u .. affBfiL'iïü: rA&iiwas&sa.fasa
isvSsS	wSSî&àfaSS Sii?ædlpi
operator and constructor and was foreman disease has w en pamouiany »e\cre on ejeçte(j jn t^e gteaj 0f Mr. Hodgins, and and wicked that 1 have no words for It. and I
ONTIAC>: flOÜSS ssssmtatssütûwbS«sms;1=¦
V«*liiy	uyvutftf eequently he did detective work up the I cent. M.d „od».th. h.veyet occurred .. . ^ ^ repUoe Ur KnoV A eon te. t ...
MAIN STSSIT,	SMAWYILLE, line of the Canadien P.oiBo. He ha. not	influeoia.^For . Iime.it we. e,erted by the iupporte„ 0f the wveral
Chris. Caldwell, Preprleler. been prosperous lately and at the query thought that men	' bu‘ candidate* agreeing to a oompromU* re-
œâEÉH	^eh^eb
“eh:;:—r	eeeebee
Store Rooms Free -bus to and from station, that the weather at times has made it factory w,n be in full operation in a few town Wl here, at the same	satisfactory to the British Uov-
=### MÆmmpmim sss
mm #@g #ma
At a meeting of the congregation of the Ooligny College.	j '.	*11	* consequently a prospect of direct settle-
St. Lukes Church, Eardley, held oil the Mr. Walter Thompson returned home | °n*-*	ment, better 1 eel in/ prevails,
evening of the Oth inti it was moved by last <date>Friday</date> morning with a bad cold, pre- "QME OF THB inconsistenvies of more»- Lisbon, January 9 —The />•>, an nth-the Incumbent seconded by Mr. John gumably la grippe.	kd tk.mfksaxcs people.	cial paper, has a lirm article on the sub-
Bradley, (people's warden), strongly sup- Miss. Jennie Swalwell, who has been Mr. Editor : ***** Should you joct of Portugal's dispute w;th England. INSURANCE AGENCY. ported by Messrs. J. Leach, C. Clarke, for over a year in Michigan, is now atem j not deem this worthy of a space in your | It says the Portuguese Government, while 1 n DDflMI VV	PFMRRHlf F (1	^ McAllister, and resolved,—That the	porgry resident in P. D. F. She is putting	columns, why, you have only to exercise	willing to negotiate in order to arrivent a
J, H. DAUwLIjIj" ' * rLmDaUafi U. congregation of St Luke's Church, Eard-	m » good time visiting among her many	one of your rights, and consign it to the	proper understanding,	will	never	com-
IPRE^K>rr9 tkf following (>mjMnios:AgTicui- ley, tender their grateful thanks to Mr. old friends and acquiantancea.	waste basket.	promise its authority in Africa by retiring
D th*Nt)lrtbeBritish aud Mercantile and the* Bh- Hector M. McLean for his gift of the or- No * report has been given to The I will only give two or three of the in- from the Slure district, and that if tho S»s SnwHess. Tbs boslneas of the IstsC. A ftailth	gan standing in the church a» a memorial	Equitt of the church entertainments,	consistencies mentioned above in this pa-	London Government insists on this it is
eleZswrfflesad H. Beatb of Quyon, transacted.	to his deceased daughter, Bliss Tiîlie Anne	which took p'ace here in the last week	per, for different reasons, the principal	with a wish to tish in dirty waters for a
_	w»rren McLean, formerly organist of St.	0f 1»89. Suffice it to eay that they were	one being, that I do not want to prove	pretext to occupy the coast. The Dia
UOTIPF I II r A n IwlERS	Luke's church ;	good. The Presbyterian 8. School fête	the truth of the charge so often laid to	states that if forced to the extreme limite
NU I lui- I U^T is 11 ¦•¦¦¦I Ve The congregation also wish to place on	was characterized by the usual old Xraaa	our much abused aex—that of never know-	of concilation Port
to Ll*D for ONI TO FIFTY TEAM record their deep regret at the removal	tree but the programme was excellent,	ing when to stop when we once get com-	international conven
Ai[0gseyt#rme. Appit to8. A. Machat, K C. L., from Eardley of Mr. McLean and family, The singing was executed with good time menced ; I believe, though, we do not
Slot %n	Caamdleml ïrlstoMjôraers ^ *nd their eenie of the loss sustained by and harmony, and the recitations and dia- generally get the credit of being as ready
Th*rv2i»°y	montk, and Quyoa ike the church and pariah of Eardley with logues commanded much applause. The j with our pens as with vur tongues, so
¦a	. ^ —.«t.	which Mr. McLean has for an many years English Church 8. School entertsinment that argument falls to the ground
been connected, and whose help in every was also interesting and though the pro- By professed teir.|ieraiioe people, good work has been so generously extend- gramme was rather long it was listened to | mean those who declare themnelves to be
with attention. The Ship Ahoy ia with- ! total abstainers and in favor of Prohibions doubt an improvement to the ever- j tion, whether they are connected with
any organisation of that kind or not. think it inconsistent for professed temper-
Municipal Hectic as.
Voie*.
l
Portage 4u Fort Kiwi.
Yours fraternally, i	Ophelia
Rhawvtlle. Oct. 24,18*
Portugal dives a Reply.
ST. LAWRENCE HALL,
MAIN ST., - - QUYON,
D. M. McLean,.Proprietor
This House Is In every way furnished to âffbrd excellent accommodation for the travelling public. Commercial men will find the 8%mpl« Rooms second to none on the road. The Bar Is always supplied with the best brands of Liquors. Wines end Cigars.
#r GOOD LIVBHY ATTACHED. 'S3
JAMES HOPE A CO.,
If-ANUFACTURIXG STATIONERS, BOO URL-lers, Bookbinders, Printers, *0, Depository of
the Ottswa Anrlltary Bible Society. Ottawa, Ont.


;

it
%
e
ugll
tion
will invoke an

I
A deputation composed of Moser#. McDougall, Conroy and Hou. fr. Hr) son waited upon the Comm asioner of Public Works last <date>Thursday</date> and asked him to subsidise a bridge over the Ottawa between a point in the county of Ottawa and a point in the county nf Carleton. The commissioner promised to give it a favor-ab e consideration.

I
ESTABLISHED 1874.
S JARVIS, - Photographer,lid;
"	141 apAsesBr., Ottawa
Resolved that a copy of the foregoing resolution be forwarded to the editor of the local papers.
I

green thrub.
Jan. 13th.

X


###PAGE###2###
)
TOPICS Of TUB TIME.
There sre ueyeu	________„
lees cities el Italy te üoeat Obvov, bel aol
There ere men y people e lee yet who weal torn*thief for nothing. A men named R. A. Heere, ol Mlnneepolls, eenl oil effort ta give three pleoee of elegantly upholstered parlor fnreltnre as an adverWeemeel lo elf who would send 90 ocnte to pay boiliw sent the mone> and got three ou tell toys with plush sente end pretty finish. The recipients were eurprleed, end yet can-nor claim that they were badly swindled, lor they got all they paid for.
It le estimated by the New York •‘Bel letio that the Investments of British capital In foreign countries for the current year will eioeed $900 000 000. Lint year the otpttel subscribed to loans and oomptnleeot all dee-orlptione amounted *> $800 745 000; In 1S87 the amount was $480 330 000, and In 1889 over $505 300, 00. The extraordinary magnitude ol the aggregate of lheee susse may give rise to doublas to the wisdom displayed In their Investments, but It leaves no uncertainty whatever as to the great wealth of a country which has so much capital to spare. In this conned'on It la interesting to learn that Mr. K»bert U ffen, the well Bat voiceless is the tuneful throat,	known etatlstlo.an, estimates the aooemu-
The wings will never flatter now,	lated wealth of U eat B it via at £10,000,.
Nor other oradle shall be know	000 000.
Save that which graces Biauty s brow tspeaking of the fact that under the new
loess of the Alaska seal ti herlse the limitation of the oa»oh Is to be reduced to 60 000 Instead of 100,(MX) an at present, the New York Sun questions the necessity for the reduction. Is eaje : -It le perfectly evident that It Is for the Interest of she Alaska Commercial Company, which wishes not only te renew ils lease Lui to do no with the leeel possible competition end on the lowest pen-el bis terms, to magnify the extent of the Illicit poaching and Its Is jury It is wail to remember that nil so frwlr made dating the punt year or ee as to the danger of extermination of the fir seal by reason of tho operations of Canadian sealers have orglnated with the Alaska
Cjb
Tfo Bird oi Her Bonnet-
dEBS
this enbjaot.
My lady was a gentle lass,
And fair .od tender M a lower
6b. .Ighed tones helplem»oth
Imprisoned In a spider e tvwer,
'«K.".’*;;.
Uoe blithaom. morn she blithely denned Her cboloeet garb, » dainty gown,
And mantle like e web ol mlet,
And bonnet like » fairy's crown :
It retted on her eon bright balr—
The silken glory tltly met—
And In Its Ida. ol oreemy leoe A bonnie bird wse ewtetly eet—
A tiny bird, with hall spread wings.
And poised upon the bonnets rim,
As skylark by hie nesc at dawn Preparing for his matin hymn.
Morris, who had never seen the «rent Mr. PUklngton, though he had made Severn!
visit, to Sidney Trench, fell n wrtnln owe
Nor was the old
clerk alone In this respect ; many a client had experienced the earns disrelish private Interview. Norris stopped halfway on the staircase and took a pinch of snuff to steady his n«rvee, and than hastened to knock at thn senior portnsr's door.
Norris found himself In the oblong room. Still at his dsek, with his white head bent and shady | over some pipers, eat Mr Pilklngton. He i all tides I did not raise his eyre ; but • stern expression came over his face, as If to hide some possible sign of emotion. "Your name Able Nutria P*
The old clerk bowed his head.
•‘Sit down.—No, no," said the lawyer, an Norris took a seat near the door. "Bring jour chair close to my desk—closer still. I
4MÏÆISSJ! SSTJffBSU'SSî'ïfi
¦MBs*
h*£* thoughtfully. “ Whnt .hell 1 dot' ? .,Ah ,,nd th, old Uwvnr fluhed e look
STM» s qwwsi Hrr - —
her own happlnem, wu due to one whose bed.mendlog Whet dny t ¦elf abnegation, ont ol love for her, bed Norris noderetood him. "Tuat day, he been so pathedo.	htotoned to expletn, ’ton whloh y onoanrato
" Take yenr time," sold Sidney, notlolog *»r oottage near So Albans and placed a llt-ber hesitation, •• to arrive at some decision. b!e girl under my wife a earn.
K vente may possibly decide lor yon ; rt> do Mr P.lklogtoeleaned boon in his chair, not answer Impulsively. Yon would do well Bat he neither glanced up nor made any til to talk the matter over with Mr. Morris ; ewer.
and when yon have made np your mind— why, dr— why did yon never write to altar listening to hie view of tn. .object- "wl-D.d yon think " said the old clerk
consult your lawyer.-What pathetically, "that «Ac wat deed ?
that ?"	This question brought e quick and some.
Whet doua II mutter to
THE MYSTERY SOLVED
••All
for un
of the senior partner
one In Re
for e
•• Could IT said Roes dreamily.
—My scheme le."mold Sidney, "that you should become the companion to a rich lady who
•* Does she live In London Î"
•• No ; In the country. But the house where she lives le little bjvoud the sub nrbv. There le a large garden, i walk», and wild flowers ; and on — — ere open heath and wooded hills."
Rosa made no reply. If the young law yer had known all her thoughts—thought, to which the had never given expression—he# ou u ht not have touohod upon a more genial •ubj sot. Could he possibly comprehend her ?
CHAP. III.—Sidney's Client.
The little Inky par lour In Took’«Court grew more Inky than ever ; for Abel Norrle eat there at hi# old desk copying diligently from morning till night. He was completely In hie element.
Not unfreqaently—more often towards the afternoon—Sidney Trenoh would look In ; and sometimes, Rosa being there, he would exchange a few words with her. And If the young girl woe absent, Sidney never failed to enquire after her of the old clerk. They sometimes met—but this occasions—In New Square or Lincoln's inn Fields ;for Rosa woe much Impressed with the number of carriages which drove up to the door of Trench, Piiklogtou, and Trench's office. They suggested quite a fashionable reception. From ten In the morning until four o'clock In the afternoon c lente never
"Y

1

;
was on rare
ceased to come and go. She tried to gain a glimpse ol Mr Pilkington more than once, but only succeeded In obtaining a distant view of his bent figure when stepping In
or out of his carriage.
Some w«eks passed by. One afternoon towards mix o'clock, when the days wvre growing longer, Rosa strolled round New Square. It was an afternoon that she long remembered ; the trees were beginning to —w green, and the sparrows chirped over
__coming summer. She woe sauntering
within these legal precincts, lost In thought ; for the spring days revived, with greater
each season, the imperfect n-mln leoenoe of her childhood ; and In the vista of these misty eoenee there had reappeared a handsome youth, her companion In sunny fields and shady woods. This youth had now grown Into a likeness of Sidney Trenoh, and she began to aeeoolate him with this companion, as though they were one and the same 1 She had not the courage to qasatlon the young lawyer ; she dreaded lest he should destroy by a contradictory word this fanciful Image of hlmeelf which she had built up from memory In her own mind. She conceived that those sunny fields—more of a dream than a reality—were too far distant from Took # CourTever to be reached again, except In Imagination.
SFSSsSSeu =—r :,
he could best closes her? She had the While talking together, they bad wand you ? '
wormeet of hearts, and the old clerk never ered out of New Square into Lincoln's Inn Norrle looked earnestly at Mr. Pilkington annealed to her better	nature in vain.	He	Fields ; and they now found themselves at	“So strong a recollection of you, sir, esld
hadconstruotsd a window garden in	her	the very entrance to Trenoh, Pilkington,	he. "that were she to meet you now -though
wrefc • and when the seeds which she had and Trench's offi *. It had often occurred	It i* twelve years ago—I doubt not mho would
planted there began to show signs of burst to Roes that a peep lueide the old house	know you again. She has a wonderful mem-
Lg into leaf she could not repress her sense would be deeply interesting ; for her 0rv."	_____
ofmtitndeand delight She would sit for cariosity had been roused by all that had	Mr Pilkington grew still mors thoughtful.	They	ssy he le	dead,
hours In this garret*boudoir ; and she would reached her ear about the great Mr. Pilk	"We shall see," he mattered—"we shall The one we loved	so	well	!
almost force: for the moment her cravings Ington and the wealthy clients who so often	see." While speaking, the lawyer slowly	Whose	holy life such a halo shed
for a more congenial home. A gleam grew weary of waiting, like so many doctor ’s	I	rose from his choir and walked towards the	Over	ell. And yet, who may toll
of sunshine would sometimes linger patients, In ths octagonal room on the stair-	I	green hoist door. Norrle roes also and stood	Or me*	or • life by the transolsnt breath ?
lor a brief half hoar In her " garden case. It was to this wry room that Sidney	watching hie movements with curiosity. Mr.	Or say,	w isn the pulse throbs oeaee	“
though never a ray	looked In al	the	now led the way. With a certain feeling of	Pilkington, without inviting the olerk to	is	death."
windows beluw • the	old olerk e inky	trepidation, for which ehe oould not account, I follow by sign or glance, stepped Into the
noriour was always In shadow.	Rosa followed. Her first Impression, os ehe I octagonal room	*•____
Happening presently to look up, the girl #eat#d herself In the chair which Sidney Abel Norris was purs ed. Whst was Mr.	C*nm% call him dead ?
saugh sight of Sidney Trenoh. He woe	placed for her, was that she had been there	l	pjklegton s object In quitting the room so	Hie word# and deeds eorrive,
crossing New Square and coming towards	before, but not In childhood : at some remote	|	eaddenly ? He had lef e the door e j er ; and	The blameless life thst for years he led
her. Having met more than onoe einoe the	period too shadowy to recall even as she had	the old olerk ^;d not fsll to bear the sound	Will hie memory keep alive ;
evening upon which he had first called at	recalled a half forgotten dream. It was	of Tolo#i Was that R?sa'e volost Norris	Some lips oan be harsh and unrefined,
look's Court, Sidney had naturally been something eo dim, eo confusing, that IS ™n- went towards ths door with eager out I Bat his were tender and always kind. I often In her thoughts ; not only playing a ished from her memory when the young law- ctretchod hand. Something Impelled him ;
3SSESS55 bsspssaq BS8SBBS5 tSSSSBS-
—¦ «-“«•- — I s; ,T
hod he never Sold her of this t—why hod he
1 cannot be mlsfcak
À smile wo# on my lady’s lip,
The love light sparkled In her eyes, While all her heart was lifted up With dr, am# of Lota's own Paradise
E
vivldn
Lite’s Parodies le thronged, they say, With tender-voiced, gay plumage d
things.
Who warble nothing else than love,
And wear Lite’s own Immortal wings.
Amid my lady’s dream, no room For one sod vision-say, of this-A nest within s rose hedge hid,
A nest thst rosebuds oared to kiss ;
the sssertleas
again
does my client say to
M She will follow your advice. "	I what angry retort 1
M Excellent I—And now,” sold Sidney, yon," said ths lawyer, "what I might think T " won’t you come and ell down In the It will not alter the situation. The girl Is clients’ room ! Mr. Norrle Is at the effioe. | alive and well : Is ehe not ?"
"Yes ; ehe Is alive and well”
The lawyer rtfl cted a moment "Hat ¦he any recollsoMon of me—any Impression of her life préviens to being placed with
panv. From what the Sun leys It cam be won how little reliance Is ho be placed on these assertions.
••Nelly Bly" reached Hong Kong on <date>Tees day</date> last on btr trip round she glebe for the New World. She arrived two days In adresse of her Itinerary, but she had five days t# wall for a steamer for Yokohama. She has oow traversed nearly two-thirde of the whole distance In about forty deys, bel Iks slowest part of ttts journey Is before bet. Not mock has yet been beard of Mise Bieland, who Is travelling in the opposite direction for the Co§mopolUan, but the greeter part of her journey so far hoe been across the Pacifie. Most people ore inclined to believe that she will be the winner in the strange race, as the obstacles In her way are met #e great as those encountered un the journey ths other wsy. Both ladles, however, are almost certain to accomplish an unprecedented
yon can
A nest where brooding mother eat With wings most tenderly outspread, Above her hopes enclosed in shell.
And waiting upon one that's—deed I
He had gone forth on lightsome wing, Bis tong had cheered her many a day : "He'll oome and feed me toon, ehe thought,
And prayed. Why not? A bird
pray
Is Eo Dead.
A Tribute lo the Memory of Reid BembikJf
" Is he dead ?
feat
••It
Parisian made botte: file# ore ed high #p on top of the newest French hate
Is he dead ?"
and more expensive materials then have
perfectly proper t# of a walking match as
Dempsey—"Don't yen like to m. Mrs. Poneonby Vx Mrs. P
jut as fond of babies
Reaben-Yse, Ills ¦peak of the proceeds gait receipts.
" Is he dead ?
Mrs.
by
—"Indeed I do 11
se I o*o be.
The Ute e c Empress of Brasil wee nearly four yean older than her heebaad, who
-ÏÜSÏ
married her whan he year» of age. Sue woe the of Finnois !.. titular King of If spies sad
Who rune may read :
Booh deed, well and truly done, Whenever It covers a human neoa,
Is s star In a crown well wea :
Mid the din and moil of the earthly strife Every Chrietly deed hath eternal life.
tint
wadding Wl
solemnised at Naples, where Dom woe represented by	‘
ceremony took ing her lifetime.
the two SioUUs, and her
Pedro
„ __________the ex Empress ew
thrones destroyed, namely, Mr own and that ef Naplm.
Everythin goes with ths spendthrift.
SS? siï^Tbê I Ml hw to obmptiy wlthe.1 . nerd of ox ancient Hall had struck I pi anation !
It le
Live within year Income, boo*
_	....	.. .....	! I very Inconvenient to live without It.
nee was comparatively Rosa placed her hand epee Mr Pilkington s I	, . |	Yen I Forevermore 1
new the chirping *f deer, opened it, and stepped forward. Bat I The ball seaeem Is here again, and sad to from Time’s mutations free, tbesparrews grew lender ; end the retreat- there n green heist deer beyond, firmly 1 say, many n man who gee# t# a ball gets on Hit seal hath life en the dealhlem shore formulated a plan for the lag rays of the setting earn—that seconded closed, the eight ef Howled her impetuosity. I a bat before it Is ever.	Of Eternity's Halcyon sea,	foreign immigrants ts
obliquely the weather beaten stone walls— She retreated lute the waiting-room In alarm I Urgent Salter—"With any sort of man- And ths simple record we place on hie prims object is to keep tumid to increase In brightness.	at her own action. Had she thought to I ™m,n| we could certainly keep alive en	breast	peasants with their liberalising fti
•• Would It lurpriee yon, Ross," said 8Id* discover the score! there ! She sank back In	A TeAFi” She—"Yen, dear,bet I would I Is the Chris tiens hops star of lift i—	somewhat similar plan, with the
icy, who fell Impelled to address the girl as her seat, as many a client had done before I eoeo#r y, comfortably dead."	I	44	At R>eV	lor motive, was proposed In 1887. The Has-
«nn
A lawyer seldom schemes without hie client e abruptly.	I in America has been started through ths I And the music floats down the dim valley education. For some unexplained
permission."	Mr Pilkington glanced toward the green I s|yort professor Henry, at the State Uni- TUI eaoh finds a word for a wing,	plan of 1887 mieosrded.
"Ami your client V	door\,“fe t,e ? Ç® T** et*ndln8 varsity of Wleoonsln. It is intended to give That to hearts, like the dove of me Deluge, The trial In O slide of agestts of ¦
» This question brought an odd laugh from near bis desk, leaning one hand upon It, and |fooroUgb instruction In dairying and cheese A message of pesos they may bring.	and railway companies accused of swindling
Sidney. "I suppose no. Shall we aeeume it, looking half over his shoulder towards Sid- I gating, including the analysis of milk.	emigrants has thrown much light apes the
assawMsg »
BSSi Wêêèê lilfill mmf ÜSÉP
erw. oxamto.l»oB !	_ no on. ooold oo.tlon. hod boom, «ore*	pr^tod *o th. 0n, u ^ ^ Beantein o( 8	tie. oompool».
flm HfiHpB Ml
‘srùfV z sa .s" -‘•¦‘Z'i-üB	ïïïïSï z
^WCPti
••Dose he liveî"
all
HM
Sh
A
bfi
liter
year one—-sw, w
00gbe comfortably dead. JBHHH
Mrs. Scrimp—'‘I do wish, John, that you would get me a new Winter wrap ; my old one is a sight to beheld." Mr. Scrimp — "H'm I Coït you wait a Utile while longer,
iy days I her, with impatience expressed In her whole Ing all I attitude. There was no remedy : ehe must
'bip
the only name she could
'Km*
;
of
ed In the west. This expedient might Improve
STS StfSZ&'S £$
bs^assstk
the general question. In Its effects epos lbs
try, the predicted eu of the white by the colored popu United States would hardly he the formation of these fresh which the race may spread. Oar nei8n^ have a grave problem In this qur«ti"n wh
&fc«rtt£58W
destinies with the great republic.
?
?
whole ooun
retarded by
tree, from
be
» .$t*,
pis. But you never you liked."
t -


###PAGE###3###
I
IepP*
LOVE AND PER L
other Hlk. I fell hell tempted bo gift no reply, bet I relented, and eeid, “All right, old follow. We U slop kero. "
The loo vu broken, and we ley down after n emrly conversation bed taken place. Mp frieed declared be won Id take the first
with the hope of tbit reearreotloe by booth log thee oo the boo4. So peteed tbU eeeolog, end a good meey mote, for we i loath to leave oar qaartere.
SOPESOf IBTJ.BfST.
Berlin baa 38,000 dogs.
The railroade employ 780,000 voters.
I
The winter became more ioteoee io cold
but that we looked for, end were Mtoolehed . An •Uotrio railw*y, eald to be the longest opportunity to go baoh, and I dl t not demur at the comparatively email amount of enow ,0 the world» MdS Md et Beds Peeth. to ole proposition. Bit wo mutt Brel find that fell, as compared to what we had been The "Country West ” Committee of Booths regular trail and some Indian lodge or accustomed to In Oatario. We certainly ton gave vacations to 8,100 poor children this _	, voyagent*e tent. Wt know well enough that **%; ieit eo well In Toronto h wt did bore, 7**r,
¦IBBSta
raSbi
eÉHWHHI
™p*. sassas priiï-KiKïï « .sas stcï 3 s s-AS2ws ïssss	•*sasum
JKÊÊÊmBm
elephants as numerous as the herds of our th|B conduct, and absolute sllenoe reigned this fim would serve f w another. Lit ns	.  crew of 800 men, of whom only 130survived.
“American bison have grcsid m olden days between ee,	try. Soms time elapsed before there was	I He remained seventeen years in aaBaglish
on the prairies of Siberia neu- chore rivers. Bat while his head got worse, at I thought, **y reply vouchsafed to the temptation	y n Unworthy Suspicion.	Prison, where he acquired a knowledge <g
and may not these spring tix>ds have carried £ observed that hit toee got better. Be was *•* down into the waters. Then came a	TP	I our language, which he still retains. Since
hundreds away and drowned them and sble to march fully as well as I, and I some jerk, then a long, strong pull. We had Mr. MoSwat picked up a doughnut that the death of Chevreuil last year he has been strewed their carcass* a along their t> inks tlm.s thought that he wcj trying to punish another I A similar tight with this, not so lay on hie plate, examined It critically, made I the doyen of the Legion d‘ Hon new He Is and at their estuaries, jest In me same way me by walking me down. Bet my toee got prolonged, took place, and there soon lay a mental estimate of Its weight and laid it I In receipt of a small pension Irom the French aa the Red River drowntd its thoaean.te of better too, and I wan determined to welk beside hie mutlleted comrade another fish, down.	I Government, and he le also assisted by an
buffaloes and strewed Its b»nk« wlto their blmdown. 8) we plodded on, and hie it. bet not this time a trout. It was a •• white- “Libella,” he said, ,4dll you make this?'1 I Englishman vh> takes an inteteet In him bodies?	Ienoe and enlklneee remained. It was arid!-	*****'!!*'&'’* kind of grayling “I did, Bitllger,” replied Mrs. MoSwat, Netwithstandiog hie great age of 99 y
I thought 1 4 never ere Toronto «gain, and 0„i0ns potion. There we were, two lonely much liked by all the dwellers within reach proudly. <TU have a whole plateful of them I hie health and faculties are good. He n$m this was my tribute at per nog so its learn- morale, holding to our course, but getting of the lakes, great or small, In North on the table in a moment.”	I	be seen on fine days taking hie promenade
log. We aid not pause at Winnipeg, ex more uncomfortable and doubtful of our own Amerie*, for of this fiek men never tire. Of Mr. MoSwat made no reply. He wa# I unaided on the Bmlevard dee Palmiers at cept to recruit supplies, bat passed on down w|K|om zoning sfmr evening.	trout one can soon have too muon. This Is thinking of the $10.000 for which he had I Hyeree, and he I» still able to describe his
ihe stream until the broad expanse of its	_ not eo with the white fish, so we were re I insured hie life the day before and ae he I recollections of the memorable battle.”
lake lay before ua. Then on its bosom we * '	joloed	at getting one.	looked at that doughnut and then at hie
voyaged many days until we oaoe to where	CHAPTER II.	We	were mere determined then ever to innoo<nt and unsuspecting young
the gigantic Saskatchewan enters It through As the blue shadows of the enow vanished make a stay at a place where we oonld have Io k of 00Id, hard suspicion settled a vast region of marsh and eodge and trass &ud g*r« n’aee to the advancing dusk of root and good refreshment Seme mere fish | face, grown fleA,where ml ^MNOal etudioe called night we ee arc hod keenly for willow olnmpe worn caught and we went to camp, light-op remembrances of Wraili deception that oonld afford shelter and fuel, and having iog a large fire near a little fressn stream the Danube, to whom bonks he was ei ii«d. oome to some suitable spot we silently halt The fish were plaeed onfthe surface of a little Thors he bewailed hie fate and the frexm ad, turned our toboggan with Its load on pool close to the fire, and there we left th wilderness, and longed for the fleshipote of edge, eo ae to afford shelter for the fire content te stretch ourselves Roms. Not so L We shot bitterns and ducks which we soon had alight. Then, taking and smoke onr pipes and look upwards vo and pelloune and geese by the score, and I ont our robe, we lay close together, 00Id in Into the dark boughs that seem to breathe Ik
wee m Paradise. And then, getting Indl* body and In manner, but rolled as near to- comfort and warmth after the enow glare et Bet west If the result should prove the I h to aid os, we canoed onward up the gether ae possible for the sake of he animal the open plains. Some of the fish w/re split discarding of ancient traditions, and the
_ioee river westward, ever westward. warmth onr bodies afforded to each other. and put before the tire on sticks, and very denial of the binding nature of hoary creeds ?
We had no Uok of food-ear guna gave % had became the mere energetic of the good they were. But what was our as tom I§ it not infinitely better that he holds in a all we reed id. Ob, the delight after our Mr©, and one evening ae we continued ov mb ment some time after supper and pfpee telllgeotly what he does believe than that » ime town life to be our own pur vcvore. U # march I found that my companion and I had keen discussed to find that la a little be shall subscribe to ancient forma*», eimpl me charm of those evening camp h «s when whilom friend was lagging behind. I saw surface pool formed by the melting of the upon the authority of great names ? He I elLn?r * ‘ ‘1 ^
•e had onr meals. We two stretohod onr |\ I am ashamed to aay, with delight •‘Now brook loe by the boat of our fire several of may act be able to pronounce the shibboleth I eeeb *d™red* rlvee before the fire, made up willow and I will make him speak,” thought I, with the fish captured hours before and frees# of his parent or teacher, bat If the principle
cpler wood, and smoked onr oip^e and malicious joy. On I went, tramping the «tiff, had become alive, and were deluding hue been faithfully carried out in every	, _ _
r*amed of further adventure and txplora- enow with even footfall, on and on At last, themselves Into the belief that they were respect, and the moial and religious eantl- tim kindness of Bjas la commending the Jem.	after we had passed some likely places for a about again to become free trout end white- moot has not been neglected, he will at reapers to drop Urge handfuls of wheat
Only one thing there was to dl,gust ue. oamp, I heard a voice behind me. Wee it fish. We uodeoelved them, but that they Ueet be an honest man, knowing why he “Now, children, she said,"Boas did Ofwn after rain along the prairie paths by indeed my friend, who had found speech at oonld oome alive again after eo prolonged ae believes what he believes, and ready ta nioa thing for Ruth, em vem
the ride of the water we earns on axtraordlo lM| f Yea, verily I ••-it Uptae, we moil apparent death was startling and new to ne. stand by his oonvlotiems, no matter how It was r ““Married her,* «
ary looking beasts or Urge tistrde. Hideous, 'stop now. Where do you wish to go T ’-ee-1 Whenever we caught them afterward we tli great the oeril or the penalty.	1 koyn '
A Story of the Canadian North-West,
'
BY THE MARQUIS OF LOESS.
le fs a curions fact that there are 200 000 propie In the United States who hare artificial legs or hands.
h» jropoan railroads are fenood In, hare no grade crossings, the engines bare nc ither bell n>r headlight, and the engineer must stand.
on

with
I here seen a very remarkable and ml-u minons report made by the P
roar ii ameers were very sound.	I Commission appointed some time ago to
>«:•>”iïlï-^sïîj'jï tïs*r.ïirru’^-^ïï.^'st'
t
empire takes its way.
'!
iear Prof

i
*
wife a
on hie
Oü The Other Foot.
He—This le • nice time of night for to oome home.
She—Couldn't help it Been hio at the lodge with the girls.
He—A ad yonVe been drinking, too.
She—Jnet a glam or too. Mrs Brown would Insist on eetdng'em np as we were coming
J aet fancy It I And why not In the as well as the other ?
7 *
M How do yon feel? " k up.”
It le ourloun that when a man drops his
E liter's
î
ta
tell

l


ma

>
###PAGE###4###



-

At C. Ross & Co’s
In order to give a new and more vigorous J	TOâOllOr TJ^clIltOd.
• I îmjHitu» to these great projects, you will	---
= îtliSrV’fflî r^rJu w*ess.
his mind whether to offur rewards for the •* twelve living children, boro in destruction of the sparrows, the lineal l*"ful wedlock, such lot to be their home-descendants of those imported by himself | *tead. many years ago.
THE EQUITY
SHAW VILLE. JAN. 16, 16»0.
SPECIAL ODD LINES OF GOODS
To be cleared out this week at special Prices.
Hhswrllle, Jsny 6. Wo.
10,000 Logs Wanted !
HELPING UNLUCKY FARMRRN.
th. i- ... .w	w^caasasawa:
speech from the throne was carried in the	di#,*,**| 0f a sjiocial committee, to
QueWc Legislative Assembly un <date>Fnday</date> unable them to distribute seed gram in morning shortly before three o flock, l|lb province of Quebec wherever the there having been an all-night session, fro*t and rajt, hid destroyed the cro|>s in which was an unusually lively one. Lead 1888 This committee has concluded its ing members of the Opposition, me uding entirely disintuiested labors with an ini-Messrs. John Hall, jr., Hon. Mr. Robert- |w%rtiality and success l>eyond all praise.
«on, T. 0. ( angram and Hon. Mr. lull This aid, so opportunely distributed lion arraigned the Government m a vigor- throughout the country, has produced ous manner, and did not hesitate to tell excellent results by preventing etnigra-Mr. Mercier that ho was held responsible tion and famine, and by supplying good for trading in race and religious prejudices gtHMj gn^n for the purpose of keeping himself in office.
Mr. Casgrain, in the course of his telling
speech, pointed out that although the Gov- **y Government considers thst it is ernniviH bonded of having a surplus, there ,low time to increase the number of inetn-whs an actual deficit of hundreds of thou bers of the Legislative assembly, and a sands of dollars. When this statements hill to that effect will be submitted to, was made on the hustings in Himouski you. The carrying out of the amend-County, how was it answered ? asked Mr. nient made last year, to the election act,
Casgrain. " it was replied in substance," granting the franchise to farmers’ sons he said, that “ Mr. Mercier was favoured &nd other persons, was prevented for the
by the Pope, from whom he had received want of the legal machinery required for	.	.	.	»	.	»
decorations He (Mr. Casgrain) and his the preparation of the valuation rolls in During the past ICW WCCKS Wlt/l 7/fOperate CIUtiyM*
arf.nas.’i: ErMs al.'sasft.JtJcrE	c ross & c0
mud for party purposes, as had been done I difficulty.	evinced much casernes# to know the I	*
by Mr. Mercier and hi» friend».” He I	™, pkovwc, s UMm.	«’K
cited La fntn* on the alleged boodling	My Government has diligently earned	been given by the people of Rhawville
which was going on in official quarters,	i on negotiations with the Federal Govern-	u'* of the workexermedat John Peter's
and upon the commissions said to have	ment for the purpose of definitely fixing	establishment Tsunexcelled by any done
been paid to friends of the Government to	the northern limits of the province, and	elsewhere in the county,
obtain a settlement of contested claims, although its efforts have not been entirely and thought it was rather a pretty show* I successful, it hopes soon to secure the ing for the |xarty of purity. The Oppoai- triumph of the legitimate claims of the in the Legislature, although numerically province, and it requests you, in s very weak when compared with the strength special manner, to carefully consider the of the Ministerial |»arty, is determined to resolutions which will be submitted to
make a strong fight during the session, you in this connection, and which are	_	_	_
Its lvadeis have begun well, and as they calculated to hasten the solution of this KEl Nfa have begun they will, continue until :he important question.	& & i 1U II U l® V 11 U !¦! Il U
end of the session.	I probable jüby system changes.	A SPECIALTY*
00
WM. SOMKXVILLK.
Shaw ville, .Ian flth, I MW
China Silk Jerney*. &c.
Trespass Notice.
To Whom it Mar Concern.
S$ppSsh	»
•H.WVU,. ARMiTRüm I DRESS goods"Sbpab,tmbnt.
000 pieces to be cleared out at half price !
"OLOKEO CASHMKRKH ALL REDUCED.
I
WAITING
About f>00 to
BLACK AND «	____
In Silks, Velvets, Gloves, Plushes Kid Gloves, Corsets,
r Velveteens, Table Linens, Towels.
TO ENLARGE THE LEGISLATIVE ROOT.
FOR TDK
VERDCT.
Clouds, Millinery
Orders to any extent carried out with promptness, combined
All Goods marked in plain Ji<jures.
. OTTAWA.
CHANGE OF BUSINESS.
Sleighs, Cutters,
ami Conveyance* of *11 kind#
We tender ovn rest thanks to those who favored us with
trouble to anyone they may bl»me tbemeelv*#.
or neatly and substantially Ironed.
roua, aud
The jury ay stem, especially in criminal matters, has been the subject of special studies and enquiries on the part of my Government. The drawbacks of the present system as regards the selection, sum-1 Chargee very Moderate# moning, qualification and the pay and i	Produce taken I* Payment
treatment of jurors, may necessitate certs n ciiai g«a which you will shortly be called u|h>u to consider.
THE PROVINCE’S FINANCES.
O’MEARA BROS. & CO.
H'urk executed on the shortest possible notice.
Cpczingr of the Qneheo Legislature.
Quebec, J&nuaiy 7 —The Législature •», dey with the usual formalities,
ute, however, being tired from ti.»eo guns pasted on the parliament I instead of from iho citadr1. Livut. Governor Angers drove up attended by an escort of cavalry and took his seat on the throne of the Legislature surrounded by the ministers and staff. After calling the members of the Assembly ho read the following speech from the throne
of the Legid Gentlemen of the Lejidatiee Atsembly :
I extend to you a cordial welcome to these legislative halls, in which you are to discuss matters of the highest interest of this country, and tender you at the commencement of the New Year my best wishes for your happiness and prosperity, and for the happiness and prosperity of your families ai:d of all the people of this province whom you represent.
My Government has decided to continue, as much as possible, to convene the legislature early in the winter, so as to allow you to conclude your parliamentary labors before the spring if you so desire
Bryeoa, Dec. W. IMS.
P. BRANEUT,
I
FREE
tfcv world. Ow Mmin eeenuslfd. tint t<i lefmderew
IS
S bÎst JÎi
mu
3
In thanking the pnhVe fur lhe vi*ry fibrin muu* ni pniruii >g* Im-mvowcU on him during the |M*t nine ) earn, the eubterlher hope* b> pivfng the very air I cleat attention to al' hind* of work In hi* line whh which he may l»e favored, to merit a continuance of tke W uhing a Merry Christmas ami a Happy New Year loall,
V
PRODUCE
ff
to on ¦	in writ lorsHlf.
a MSboe* Only theoo wS« write
r« Mil wre -*#
Gentlemen of the Legislative Assembly;
The public accounts for the year ending the 30th June last, as well as the ordinary and supplementary estimates, will be submitted to you without delay, so that j their consideration will not retard your parliamentary labors. You will doubtless be pleased to learn that the receipts and expenses again show a satisfactory surplus in favor of the former.

(h* rhenrr All yoe hsvotodole
I
?ante
EY
40 ind 43 New By Wfcrd, Sforket,
«hoM who roll —?o«r »«|h end tti<«eo oiowiil ywi Tl%*
* Ho-
R‘‘N|M‘ci fully,—
ATI
¦foam* of ihu mUfiieomoni ehowe the smell end of the tole-
OTTAWA, ONT.
JOHN LESTER.
ative Council :
Hon. Gentlemen
Shaw ville, Dec. 19.14*0
DIALIII IW
Bfltter. Egg*. Ch
aæsws
•to., sts.
fWT Oi>ol* received on consignment. Quotation given on enquiry.
JAMES G. CARSWELL,
Ottawa, June 1. 1SN».
REWARDS TO AGRICULTURIST*.
A proclamation has been issued putting into force the act of last session establishing distinctions for agricultural merit and you will be called upon to provide for the necessary expenditure in order that our agriculturists may receive the rewards to which they arc entitled. You will also be requested to increase the number of businesses to be placed at the disposal of our pupils in our agricultural schools, in order to enable a greater number to attend such schools and to further popularize the theoretical and practical
instruction required fur our farmers' ] commenced business, begs to draw public attention to the fact that he Is thoroughly ?•quipped to execute all work entrusted to him In
MANUFACTURER OF
: BOOTS
SHOES
CAMPBELL'S BAY, P.Q.
5
it.
THE JESUITS' ESTATES MATTER.
TN thanking those who have favored bin 1 with their very liberal patronage since b
On the 5th of November last, the date agreed upon, the province paid, to those who were entitled to it, the $400,000 granted by the act of 1888, asking the
¦bare of tho Roman Catholics in the set-1 permanent exhibition» in Montreal
tiennent of the Jesuits' estates, and a dis Honorable Gentlemen ,/ Me Lfjiil.itire charge was signed, containing the assign- Council:
ment and subrogations authorized by law. Gentlemen of the LejUlatire Auemblu :
Mi,”S srsssl 1 -x- “r nr
Slil IIS
seem reasonable. A bill fur the definite I cl ^ ° " 1 n rea * disposal of these objections will be submitted to you. We should all rejoice at I The collection of amounts levied upon the final and satisfactory settlement of municipalities for the maintenance of the this important question.	(irsane in asylums presents difficulties
night schools for the working classes which render it almost impossible, and A very earnest movement ha, recently my Oovem.nent will submit a bill to you manifested itself in this pmvince in favor wh,ch T'"' m th.s respect eatabliah a of night schools for the working classes '"T Just and rational system, which My Government considered it wise, and w, .ho^ urbing existing contracts,
even necessary, under the circumstance., w,“ effecf »	,
to encourage auch school, in the cit.ea of Y,.’u.	\ .*"* !nced- ,devo,te
Quebec and Montreal, and you will be	¦tient,on to the study of th
asked to vote a special grant for that pur- "T" <lue,t‘0knl' Your l>»t"otmm w,l
2	6	1 assist you in the proper performance of
your official duties, as your experience as legislators will assist you in endowing our province with wise laws, calculated to assure its happiness and prosperity. tu , After the Lieut.-Governor r™*.
^ I speech, both houses set to work on for " mal business such as receiving reports of elections, appointing standing committees, etc. Mr. Tesyier, the new member for Rimouski, was introduced by Mr. Mercier and Jiîles Tessier and Mr. Eng-The revenues generally, and especially land, the new member for Brome, was in-those from Crown lande, have gone on in- t reduced by Messrs. Tall ion and Robert crossing during the past three years, and son. the latter, that is the revenues from the Grown lands, now exceed one million dollars per annum. This is very satisfactory, and there is every reason to hope that this state of things will continue.
sons.
FIRST-fLlSS STYLE.
FOOTWEAR
of every description made, and A One mate rial used.
Produce taken In Exchange,
A Call Solicited
jas. c. carswell. i Having a large stock of Mens
Overcoats, Ulsters, Pea Jackets, Heavy Pants, Shirts and Underwear, which must be sold during the next 30 days, we are reducing to
THE CAKE or THE INSANE.
P.8.-No Credit.
Campbell’* Bay, Dec 9, list
DUBBEBS
our
and
improving public roam.
ity of improving the roads in the country has induced my Government to further encourage the atoning of our public roads, and you will be asked vote an
overshoeS
MOCCASINS, &C.
Great Bargains at
The n
WHOLESALE PRICES
5
as the goods must be cleared out in season.
appropriation for that purpose an experiment. The stoning of these roads will necessarily entail the abolition of turnpikes and toll bridges.
INCREASE IN REVENUES.
Hodgins&Son.
J
The house then adjourned.
MASSON
Robe Lost.
Shawville, January 6th, 1890.
T OflT on the road between Mr. Henry
______	__ „	_	AJ Knox’s and Hliatvvllle. on the 2*th Dec-
COLONIZING PUBLIC LANDS.	I ember last, a grey Hlelgh Kobe. The finder
The work of colonization is successfully will be suitably rewarded by leaving
and energetically carried on, and several j “meal “>1. o«ce, or at Me Oai!i£to**H
powerful companies, organized by influential persons in Canada, the United States, and even Europe, have applied for public lands for colonization purposes ,
in the province. If the* com panic, offer I	Z ttSTP.*
suitable guarantees, they should have 11 and ix on Uv* 3rd rang*» of Thorne, without every facility afforded them, so that they flreL obtaining my l^rm,pgppji XOOOKV may aid us in settling our public lands. Thorne, Jan. 9th, HCC.
the
&COS
102 Sparks St. OTTAWA.
Clarendon, Jan. 14, i860
Trespass Notice.
^
###PAGE###5###





K:* :
>
, - .
$ «H	"



is à





< •*
Big Alteration
THE PEOPLE’S
Grocery Store
SHAWVILLE,
AITS
CLEARING SALE
J
\
|| E WAS REMINDED.
Of Dry Goods and
ALLOA, John! Where are you boo nil for
Interrogated
II
GEORGE HOGGING, JR

Ready made Clothing,
•« early this moruln*
Farmer A, a* the former was driving past his gate In the direction of Nhawvlllo.
Farmer It “Oh. I'm Just going down to Hhawvllle to square thing* up a bit. You aee. ____	m m -	I we've had a gu«ni harvest this rear, and &
Who keeps in stock the heat quality of Goods.	kZ dish", .hneho“
___	"	- est man la to settle np what he owes."
¦J
AT

\
Farmer A.—*' Right you are there. John ; ami bv the way that remind* me of n bill that I owe Tit km ut. the harms* man, wlileh should have been paid before this. I'm sure he experts It, so I'll Just five you the money for him. A fellow muai ntlrk to hi* word If be wants to keep hie good name."
“That’s so." remarks Farmer II.. as be pockets the money tor Joe and drives off.
:POINTERS:

)
Everyone invited to cone in and look around. Hundreds of Bargains that will interest pay and you.
Sale to Commence on <date>Thursday</date>,
January 16th, at
HARDY S, - - - RENFREW.
FOR THE PEOPLE.
Axes, Saws, Rope, Cow-chains, Belli, Whips,
Skates and General Hardware,
LOWEST PRICES, AT SHAW'S.
!
I
Teas, Sugars, Tobaccos, Syrups, Fish, and General Groceries,
Fresh Goods
large Stock,
I
Sale of Land for Taxes.
Public Notice.
LOWEST PRICES, AT SHAW'S.
•eels. Shoe*, Rubber*, Fell Goods, Mitts and Moccasin*,
LOWEST PRICES, AT SHAW’S.
Avis Public.
NOTE THE FOLLOWING »
Double Thick Tobacco, (Seven»)
Covl Oil.................
Team.....................
Lance Tooth Saw», (per foot)-
Ax em, from..............
4«c
20
i
}
PROVINCE OK QUEBEC,
Municipality op the County op Pontiac
"PUBLIC NOTICE is hereby given that the land» herein-A after mentioned will be bold by public auction at the Council H»1! in the Village of Bryson, in the County of Pontiac, on WEDNESDAY, the Fifth day of March next, at ten o'clock in the forenoon, for the aseeiament and charges due the municipalities hereinafter mentioned, upon the severs I Jot* hereinafter described, unless the same be paid with cost* at least two days before the day of sale.
PROVINCE DE QUEBEC,
Municipalité du Comte de Pontiac
20 and . 25
75
75
A Vis PUBLIC est par le present donne que le terre ci ¦ax apres mentionné* seront rendu par encaa public dans la salle du Conseil dans le village de Bryson dans le Comte de Politise, MERCREDI le Cinquième jour de mois do Mars prochain a dix heures de l'avant-midi pour les coti tiens et charges due aux municipalité ci a près désignés a molli qu'elle de soient payér art c les frai» au moins doux jour avant le jour di dessus désigné.
1 have Inet received » lot of Tel which I am offering at 25 cent*, end I am satisfied It 1» Hit» Im«ki value to lie had InShawvlllt. Pieese call and gut Mtmple.
Te arrive la a few days, s ease of Ladles1 Tweed dUp&wia at S6 coots per pair. Keep them Id view.	____
J. H. SHAW.
ShawvtUv.Xov K,
STOVES
Etendu. Montant Eiteiit. IA .is *int.
Nom mur le Hole de Tsxe N.tUid on Asiofmiui uf It*•!I
Kan % IK off*
Nom de Municipalité.
N.miu of Municipality.
Lot
61 M 18 04 23 53 38 CO
2	14 25 02 40 43
3	84
18	04
25 48
36 07
•î 25
19	17 3 13 Il 7D
10 61
STOVES.
100 A
3
West
STOVES.
Michael Kennedy.......
Bruno Dupont..........
Late John Hudson.....
Æncaa Kennedy........
Edward Robinson.......
William Meehan........
Henry Hades...........
James Wilson..........
George Armstrong......
John Iiobillard.......
Maximo 8t. Joan.......
Albert Cone...........
John W. Hodgina.......
Samuel McDowell.......
Louis Barbeau.........
Thomas Dagg...........
Prentiss & Cole.......
John Richison.........
Walter Craig..........
Heirs Mathew Sinclair..
John Knox.............
James Grace... ;......
John Dale, Jr.........
John Lafferty.........
Estate W. H. Mousseau.
Voucant Desjardines---
I Estate of Patrick Komis |Estate A. Poppin.....
Heirs late Thomas McVeigh
William McVeigh..........
Chai lea F. Cono.........
fJohn A. Mohr............
Allumette Island do	do ..
do	do ..
Chapeau Village... Waltham & Bryson
Chichester........
Clarendon.........
2
East part 45
21.......
South part 30
6
90
East
104
2
100
1
W
The undersigned begs to call the attention of the public to his large assortment of Stoves, comprising Double, Cooking Box and Parlor Stoves ; also to his extensive stock of
100
50
5
300
9. W. half 24 ami 25.............
N. E. half 25....................
N. W. half 3.....................
S. E half 25.....................
S. W. half 20, N. E. half 23, S
uarter 27..................
. half 11...................
VV. half of N. 1$. half 10......
Part 8. W. half 25...............
N. E half 20.....................
N. W. quarter H..................
8. W. half 6 ....................
N. E. half 25 aud N. E half 20..
S. E. half 17....................
S. E. half 18....................
Part S. W. halves 19 and 20......
N. XV. quarter 1.....
8. XV. half 20.......
Part 8. W. half 25.
N. W. half 5.........
R. half 22 ..........
N XV. half 3.........
N. XV half 7.........
N. E. quarter 14—
N. quarter 23........
K. E. half 25........
11 and 12............
8 half 0.............
N. half 17...........
N. half lb...........
N. XV. quarter 19....
8. part 18...........
8. part 19...........
8 part 20............
N. half 5............
N. half 7..........
Centre 13............
Lot 2, Calumet Hoad “ 102 Water Lane.
8
t
100
10
do
100
6
do
100
12
do
i
11
250
9
do
n:5
12
100
10
Tin and Agateware, Paints, Oils, Glass & Putty.
do
50
11
do
05
11
do
100
12
do
i
9
150
HE KEEPS PLOUGHS, CHAINS, FURNACES, COOLERS, AXES, SAWS, CUTLERY, LOCKS, BOLTS, AND ALL KINDS OF SHELF GOODS.
do
10
200
17 10
21 A3
37 20
11	24
8 A3
12	94
13
do
200
8
do
100
4
do
(Xi
IN STOCK AND MADE TO ORDER.
5
do
50
5
do
o
100

5
do
35
2 02
11
do
100
10 00 17 25 19 39 27 50 23 48
6
Litchfield
• • • •
100
6
do
Highest Price paid for llides, Pelts and Old Metal.
100
7
do
100
QUYON.
DEDUCE T. MOHR,
7
do
50
(»
do
!
1
9 50
Quyon. Nov. let,
do
2
40 25 13 09 4 99 3 48
1	75
2	iu;
2 44
I 1 79
13 40
Ï2 OS J
Oni
7 SO
2	43
9 91
3	27
3	94
4	19
7	22
8	77
5	MS 4 90
4	40 7 58 3 m
3 OH 3 A3 12 37 3 38 A 80
5	JO
1
Clothing !
do
100
3
South Onslow North Onslow
I IOU
7
100
7
do
do
50
7
do
do
Clothing !
76
8
do
do
71
8
do
do
51
8
do
do
100
0
John Tierney Patrick Dolan
<to
The undersigned desires to inform the public that he lifts just received a large stock of
100
8
do
100
8
do
• • • •
do
William Dsgg..
Edward Gagnon George Knight.
do ...........
George McLaren..... Armstrong or Merleau
Thomas Corrigan....
Faloon Corrigan....
Michael Cooney.....
James Cooney.......
Joshua Coffin.......
John Daley..........
William Dagg.......
John Dagg..........
William Hassard....
Patrick Kelly......
Lyons Hardwick.....
Robert Lucas.......
John Murphy.........
George H. Parley....
James Roney do
James Reynolds Walter Rimer . J Walton Smith, or F. E. Rimer
John Stevens*.............
James Stevens ............
James or Devine Tubman....
Richard Hodgins...........
John Bradley..............
F. Armstrong or H. C. Leggv John S. Murphy............
Portage du Fort
READY-MADE CLOTHING,
do
do
1
«4
do
“ 1 of 2 Clarendon Itosd “	1 Water Lane........
e • e •
COMPRISING
do
Suits, Overcoats, Pea Jackets, Cardigan Jackets, '	Pants and Vests,
(Tbe latter for working or drew* and wold separate If required.)
Complete line of inderwenr, Top Shirts, Ac.
do
103
10
E
Thorne
56
31, 32
34..................
K. in Gore............
N. E. half of J. in Gore
S. W. half E G.........
N. B. half H. I., Gore. R half F. O
W
do
07
W
do
92
1
do
62
Also ft
1
do
118
1
IX addition to thk amove he IIab a full stock or
do
127
1
dry goods,
do
118
It
1
do
88
20
1
do
and a splendid assortment of
104 J
N. half 4, 5
2
do
PRIME FURS,
• •
199
DC
1
do .
200
21, 22..................
F. half of D., Gore....
F. halves 42, 43, all 44
39, 40..................
R. half 49.............
F. half E. F...........
• •
2
do
52
wh as Cans In a tier and Persian Lamb, Gauntlets, and Muffs,
aacu » w	Aleo aii kind# of Imitations.
2
do
250
1
do
200
W
do
1 28
60
4
do
II 54 0 44
3 12
G 19
2	41
3	24
3	24 2 TO
11 67
4	25
G 75 8 30
104
w.tch™. clocm.	AND ornam-ntal^o»,^KNivett0
2
do
75
3f>
w
do
62$
8. w. half G, Gore 8. E. half 7 and 8.
CALL AND INSPECT STOCK.
. Farm Product token in rrchangt (or Good*.	_ ____ _ _
ELIAS HOLSTEIN -------------SHAVTVILLE.
i
do
103
E
do
• •
89
4
K
do
100
46
W
do
100
45
K
do
100
43
2
llwstrh la the wodd
# #
livery stables,
do
F
210
K	I	37, 38 .
9	35, 36..
4	Part 22
do
174
do
i
A
do
100
%
42
1
Que.
do
*»4 S»e« • «’»«•.
wi'h wurke sn4	«V
SEAWVIME, .
fequal ruine. Us #arh lace lit f e#u
Office of the Municipal Council of the County of Pontiac,
Bryson, 4th January, 1890.
WILLIAM G. Le ROY,
Secretary-Treasurer, County of Pontiac.
#
{

Bureau du Conseil Municipal du Comte de Pontiac. 1
Bryson, 4 Janvier, 1890	)
WILLIAM G. UROY,
Secretaire- Trésorier, Comte de Pontiac.
^8Sm
¦ l-J
MmpiM. M well All Hie w*rk ye*
_ w* ill **
m the watch, are frff
t>ai the best of drivers.
m hM/n ** ItkMMbwii r
f
Ai**fUen«l «i»l|flih-nie*4
•uJ tk<M weere

>
###PAGE###6###
\

A BATTLE 18 THE DABI.
THE FÀRBOB OF tit. LOOIA.
reeable reeldeeoee If mot the strongest
The bmlldlegi
as
oon’re poison ’ Walking N ender the olr cnmiMDce, very palnfel, owing to rapid I are ¦¦«Uadi New Wallen In the Wee# Indies. I ewel log, bet it duel be done. Sometimes deelpnsd with teete.

masonry or brlok walls, ana
A Marvel#»! BxpleCI aâ Beeeâa» V» fa Mtr White I righting» Tarfceaai Merle.
A» was at the opening of » ulorloue crop! I the victim, In drawing himself away from The British taxpayer, In conjunction with
"""I	Ij£~j?s3rlsr®?
HnHwH
sSS3SKS3 ssSSSrSSSfeiS-rsüiS A If	bg«sss=ar«
m tel
Th K	portant vdn; for In euuh oases human skill dies mast not shave or wtar shoes or shirts	th*re wf—. * flah ,sods S1**® 1® front of ue.
....... ».»......... |	Ksi'.‘i?7S3,i ï7X’M?„",7;	%m®m	.^^sttfasr usii!
sod most luxuriant (n tropical growth. \N « Libat also tolls us that many attack the Chinamen dressed In white, moving among	SsffÊMVrHX6h# dr,t '<1 *adrons, had euooeeded, thanks
•aw no snakes, however, and could find no l#rpeni»# *oun(i more drastically by g aryl- the gayly dressed throngs of every Chinese	§2&ÎÛ5&	60 the darkness, In planing It# stood# right In
authentic account of any one here f,av,DH their throat wah epirlt and then such* city. And when a Cblnamen is iu mourn	F-$l• k[-tRA	I the middle of the enemy. Unfortunately,
been killed by a fer de lame, that being lBg the venom from the bitten part, repeat- log he braids white allk Into his hair and	xjultil £: At	I the rockets buret without rising. Probably
tiie snake of which Froudo tells most won- I thl* operation over and over and pressing has even the eoleeof his shoes painted white.	they had got wet and the heat had split
derful stones In He account of this island I ftrollu(j the Injured part at the same time. He entirely discards for the time all things	jfljftt?IÆ gvSt ^yjft	them. However, the explosions frightened
A Sergeant of H^yal K agin sere whom I	risk is great in case any of this venom of red oolor, and he take# the red coloring	8$g8l§gS*5|lf®@^	the Turkomans, and had
questioned told me that he had been here gete into the system by swallowing or other- • eff the furniture of hie house- Red le the	f	forming for a moment a little opening in
three and a half years and bad surveyed the I ^ jje B|g0 tene Qf s #nBge called the oolor of prosperity in China. It means lucky,	I the mass of the ocmhatante,
hill on the north side of the hailnr, where ooulemore which appears later under other and the ordinary Chinese visiting card is a I	LINGERIE.	j “Then 1 heard behind me an energetic
earthworks were now being erected : that nB wh’ose especial delight it is to attack «trip of red neper ae long as a government	- ?oloe ' ^ w*7 v end two oompaÿee of
I Fe vr jSSri5^ iF-E	I
asms In each oases by Mr. Fronde, tamely I eAOtl ttago in the frog’s pro^rsss baiug mark are. The Chinaman who would not put on I 2 Is one of a satchel sh «do In nlneh M,owsd. 4 Five I* a little farther, and yet rammed his rgty head into the matted grass ed the extension of the skin of the snake, mourning for hie father would he arrested, jjt ej'wlth	ed d wlth brocaded rib father, and then farther still, to the right
In the hope oi escaping, and in that position I Wbi0h was ten feet long Should one of and In Corea a man ie expected to clothe him- . ith * bow of the asms and three where I wa\ one volley after another and the Major walked over him. Not only that, [bee# beasts chase a mar, the right tMng	self In yellow eackloth and trot around the	ehort ostrich tips on top ^	ftt lse6»	the distance near the gardens, we
bat the death dealing monster remained In I todo, eaye the reverend gentlemen, ie to	country under a hat ae big ae a dlshpan, hold-	3 |e 0f seal plush satin lining feather	heBrd	rolling of the cannon. Right
that oetiich-like position until the Sergeant iLüg, for the ooulemore gets so muon head- log a fan before hie face for three years after j eduinv and a bullion cord with teasel 1 The "*****?# rounds were fired by the 00mpen*
L * gone back fif y feet, picked up a stick, WBy on him that be Is unable to double rap- the deU 1 of any near relative. During this *bape may ^ copied from the illustration. I<e oesr whloh I was, and In peace time, broken hie back with It. Ihe negro | jg|- ; in faot, ii as helpless ae a wolf ou the time ht can do no business, cannot engage In 1 An Interlining of wadding sprinkled with dorln8 reviews, I haf# often heard weree boys who acted ae our guides were voluble ^ running alter a skater. When the marriage or attend any festivities. Cuina sachet powder and satin or surah outer ^ring. Between the eeoond and third rounds in painting the savage qualities of the fer de COulemore and tor de lines meet each is men do 11 ago to theaters during their mourn- ||nl| necessary and a layer of crinoline * *rooP o! Turkomans daehed through the lanoe and assured ue that many were killed overcome by the desire to swallow the	irg period and the law to a certain extent	g, *2d „ben a fi&t shape lime No#. 2 or 3	Bret company and killed four soldiers, hut
by their bites, but, as I expected, they could other's head immediately and thus lutfjoate	regulates the mourning customs of Japan.	^ preferred.	‘	thie dU	not prevent the regularity of the
not refer to a single case of which they had him, sacking tie reeo of the body down During me urnlngthe leading tffiolals of many jfo. 4 Ulttgtratee a finish for a low corsage firing. The company was there, standing personal knowledge. My well Informed Ser- I afterward In leisure moments.	ot the ooantries have the right t> resign, and |0 hertha style It consiste of a frill of laoe drml7 M N it had not even remarked this
géant said that if the bite was attended to L that noticed In 1604 what Oder, the natu.- not long ago LI Hung Chang,the great vice- four io0he« wide ending In a jabot on the 1,ttle »P^e, waiting all attention for am-even within twenty four heure the victim B|ief| gByi 0| this snake under another name, roy, asked to he excused from hie duties as right side and headed by a ruons of narrow * other oommand to fire, need not be laid up more than a month, and	when bitten by bis venomous enemy, Premier of the Chinese Empire In order that t|bbon loops A ribbon bow is placed at
that lime joioe was an excellent thing as an he rube himself against an herb called “ La he might go off and mourn for hie mother. the hack ofthe left shoulder and one at the aoddote 10 the poison.	m.l-nomme., herb. fine, pointue, u» z douce	- —- end el the j.bek, mingled m'th fl ,wen.
-2°.-snaf mmC k,.*5S:iX;’uK7, -,.sism-
how this fer de lanoe bunts his human prey M ^ Bnt|dote to the bite of the fer de lanoe. Annie wi the gowden ookt, . >   Torchon laoe. shirred at the top. tied with a eou6ed ,n ^roed daylight and by special word
by creeping along a garden path until tne both Mr. Breen and Pore Labut had Braweet Isas on Lyle braes,	? ribbon on the left side, and the spaces oi oommand. It was the regular volley fir-
guileless tourist falls foul f t him, when in uve(j at ieset ten tears in the Antilles before j Whore, upbringing maog the rocks, between the open strings are worked with lo6 which had shown the battalions their the flash of the eye the fierce boast has reoordlng their opinion# of the snakes there,	| He ills duster ws the slaee ;	washing embroidery silk, or cotton In cross	PUoel- If the Bring had been confused and
stubbed him with farga that never do less and M neither Mr. Fronde nor Mr. Coleridge	Proudly waves the thistle braw,	stltohdeeigna. 7	irregular, the troops would not have been
shun kill. Coleridge, a nephew of the poet, had spent much more than us many hours Golden broom the poebs praise ;	B&U gown sleeve# are trimmed with *ble to discover their whereabouts In Ihe gen-
who visited ihe island in 1825, gives the ^ Luoia, the weight of evidence appears	But the taireet flswer o a'	ribbon epaulet# that ore often 00mposed of	•rid ohsoe. In the camp lay the dead and
gentle reader a shudder by saying that not t0 me% st least, ovsrwhelmlngly In favor of	u the lass o Logie braes.	j § of on# ottiamr	with another	fcbe wounded Turkomans and Kneel sue. The
even on horseback is the ii qoi.itive traveller the statements of the first quoted. We may	,	-	smartly clustered and set up on the top of cbleJ oi detachmsnt, General Oalowatn-
reasonably conclude, therefore, that snakes, P	through ths heaoh and whin, ’ the srm A ribbon brooghe from under the cheff'.^?d th? ch,*f ,,f hU etâtr; were both
known ae the wood .lave, whose Dite Is as I like .harks, wolves, and other aavage ani	A„Su, while she keeps .m* \\ ®rm to the top, tied In eW, and the loops *0ttnd*d	OT6e* Jn of
Mw0 «###= mmm?
thl. rahiwit more .ntho.ii.UT. then the imi tUn of theobjMt tb.y meet	#	Two strep. o( .boot two Inohe- wide In the.	. _ . ...
of on Bogt-wr 8eree.ot	'	The dedre to Imprem the render . Un.gln- winter eoon will pom nwey,	meteriol of the gown, one over the .boni-	The Grant Stake in Afrion.
zssiba&jbjslz: b=£-,ï5 STsSÿSrasJSs Essÿjtk	p £b	E3Hi
oolf d.scendad, and thereupon onoe more down on them." In the wrenteenth con t„ tbe center end leveled on end bonded on the oeooelon of hi. third nepti.1. by hi. them ooder EoelUh Utlaeno. with not 508
atmu's %	a a sseuflarsft rr rAssrusraas -sast & srafcss-
vrssssf- “'*¦	asr. tt sssisiz ass __________________asasr	;-.r
wmm
ssitjss;	£•% x-rv- ?t
nuoeesarily fatal, and that the method re I and witnessed H oard’s enrrender.	across her room without slippers, and a pin By a quick shot he had jaut rescued her £>1» Pnrt*»*|,ak^	™ k* l^snnah#»
sorted to by native medicine men, or hush I Since the British Government has changed ran Into one of her feet It was pulled eut I	«*wf®hee	of	s	bear.	_A	fche _« ,l	'
dsotnrs, ee they are called, Is ae follows :	I	its mind and concluded to put 8a. Lucia in at onoe, but the foot eoon swelled, with moat I “What were	your thoughts when Brain J-ntre fmm	(J* n if*
•'Fwet, bind the bitten member strongly I a state of defence the barracks on this lofty violent pain, and a doctor was called In. He I oemmeooed to equerse ?” was his Inquiry. d i . , p	10 ”	*•
eevfcti or eight fingers’ width above the I pinnacle are belnr put into habitable rhape. I declared It to be a case of bleed poisoning, | “(,n- ( ’aarlie, I ibon^hti ef you 1”	P
wound and walk home as quickly as posai I Carpenter# were at work putting down fl tor I caused by the colored wool of the stocking, ble, without touching any 1 ding to dilnk, ‘a I log, and It cannot he many months before He ordered her to he taken at onoe to an meâne du’on ni veuille hoirs de ea propre I this rain Ie converted into one of the most I hospital, where thefoet was amputated.

€
r /
h
A
5L
I
the osofusloa for It wee too

J
the resell of
end
When the sun, with the rapidity oenal In
the hor no, oar troop woe _	found to be drawn up In a eemlolrole, one
of open I 00,11 P*n7 by the side of the other, In an order ae exeat as If the mac <u avre had been ex-
the
ron
SAPE PROM A SAVAGE MONSTER
bJ
1
P

nut
Though It blooms nose, ihe ram blossom celled the national flew
y a patriot's t quit# jet to ^ ,
A short acquaintance—the man who Ie always wanting to borrow money.
y
!

###PAGE###7###
The Turtle MoueUIn itogion.
Money to Loan
, 2) • J L JONES, WOOD ENGRAVER
V io Kino Sj REE t E-as r
TORON id. CANADA
ENGRAVIN
*1 it*
The Btor? ofs Year.
A Utile Utlld Id raiment while Wee sent to me o*? day With meeesge from the King of Light •• Thy core I will repay,
If thou wilt keep her germe it bright Along the nerrow wey."
TOLD BY OLD 801/8 FACE.
I

III'
^ AUVt RTISINC
I Î • V1
ment lend, now open for settlers, In the Turtle Mountain region of Dakota. Here . wee raised the wheat that took 8ret ore •
Exposition. Rich
Inter*
I
PURPOSED.
eetlng Pacte.
Tne meet pronounced effects of n solar dleturbanos are felt as It appears by the rotation on Ite axis and ae the disturb
*"%* “re?? tb* ' œ*rMUn Th* .U I w, wtnd.rwl forth, lb. ChW «><! i : Md * half day. b.twwn .pp.ar.no. by ro Bat .o, .11 o.r.lw «own, taUon and m.rldlnn pomng. are marked by ; b«d«l not bar plain tire .Igh,
.»"ror“-	#r •artkqnakw. A., hart by thorn and .too.,
Alut m.rldlao pa*..g. th. «term loflo.no. 0r chilled by enowdrlfti piled on hlgb, cl a solar disturbance appears to cease. In this use of the word storm all the other
phenomena are Included. All are kindred. I We wstdered on ; more fair the land, When solar dlatnrbauoee follow each other	8wester the fragrance round.
In rapid succession the storm period le pro I clasped again her little hand, longed. Too effects of solar disturbances Ana sped o'er dewy ground,
Whtvh bream out on the sun's hemisphere Heedless of clouds the sky that span nod, turned toward ae pr<x no# sadden and power | O; wild boast# lurking round, let effooto In our atmosphere. Storms known	WjBM
aeoloud burst haves been most frequently I Still on we went, through gorgeous ways aotod In connection with these sudden out- O'er sunny vale and hill, hursts on the sun's faoe. Ae a rule the While all too swiftly passed my days marke of solar dlsturbanoe cannot be seen By gleaming brook and rill, until the storms on the earth oease. The And I lorgot In noontide e blszs spots form after the storm producing crop- To guard the Child from 111.
2
On tori') Firmer* dwlro-ie of ^tytog off es el ns high lntore»t-heering mort *ee. or intendlug to bold
I linnniir	- YOUR •	grehiaede oek for bettor prloea een obtald Nenej
I IflPnOVE PENMANSHIP ÇZSSW2WftSfM,“ere“	‘
I Book kef	8 lorthend, Tyi>ewrltlnffJHH|HHHkHfl|^^H^|^|
Buitneae Educe11 n 'by attending (day or ever-lag)
CAS 41*14% lU MhMH rtltKBMlTW,
Public Llhrery Building, Toron o
THOM MRHOliH.
(Officiel Reporter York 1 o inty Court )
mlutn et New Orl •oil timber In mountelne, good eohools, ohurohee, congenial society. For farther Information, maps, rates, apply to F. I. Whitney. 0 P A T. À , 8t. Paul, Mien, or J. M. Huohlns, 4 Palmer Hones Blk Toronto.
LONOJN&CANADIAN 10AN 6 AGENCY COY
J. r KIRK, Manager.
•I
TORONTO
103 BAY ST.,
President.
She ottered weary moan.
The New York Tribune refers to the poisonous character of the oleender. The warnleg Is timely. The oleander le beautiful, but It le poisonous, and we often wonder that, where there ere children it dose not oftener do demago. We would not have one oa the premises.
KNITTING MACHINE ALLAN LINE

KEEP
ROYAL MAIL STEAMSHIP»
Send for Illustrated Catalogue and thle advert!»#ment with your onerf or
our NRW BIBBKB a d we will
l allow you
THE PIONEER CANADIAN LINE.
' And still toth'1 front In regarl to the pr.ivleloo made i lor thi safety and ounlort of Its customers.
Weekly Mulling* Between Liverpool, fill* low nn«l the Ml. Law rrure A Inrtntgkt-ly Mervlre from London during Mummer Slonlk*.

110 PREMIUM DISCOUNT
All Hen
A NT *V>
ADD»:##—
young, old, or middle aged, who find them. ••Wee nervous, week, end exhausted, who are broken down from exoeee or overwork, resulting In many of the following symp toms :	Mental depression, premature old
aje, lose of vitality, lose of memory, bad dreams, dimness of eight, palpitation of the heart, emissions, lack of energy, pain In the kidneys, headache, pimples on the face or body, Itching or peculiar eeneatloo about the •orotom wasting of the organs, d'zz ness, spooks before the eyes, twitching of the muscles, eye llde and elsewhere, baenfoloese, deposits In the brine, lots of will power, tenderness of the scalp and spine, weak and flfcbby muscles, desire to sleep, failure to be rested by sleep, constipation, dullness of hearing, loss of voles, desire for solitude, excitability of tenper, sunken eyes surrounded with LEADER CIRCLE, ollf looking 'kin, eto, are all symptoms of ¦¦¦ debliity that lead to insanity and death unless cured. The spring or vital force having lost Its tension every function wanes In consequence. Those who through abuse committed In Ignorance may be permanently cured. Send your addr tsa for book on all peculiar to man. Address M. V. 50 Front Street E*et, Toronto, Ont
CREKLMAN BROS., M fgs
? NTHIS
Mail Steamers iua between Liverpool and I’ortiaeW v Halifax during winter Glasgow «learnerssal thi vtigbout the year to Boston and Philadelphia, eaB
ABSOLUTELY NO LIMIT I &;%%%"'ZLb. ^ a
to the uwe* of the wonderful H. BOUE LIKE, oor. King and Yonge St#., Toronto Convertible Paaket. MO articles H 8c A. ALIaN, Montreal, or to the local agents h» In one. Used everywhere for your countv.
rything, Hound» big, don t____________________.
w	Put you'll »uy It's cot iret
when you see It. Agent* experienced or fnei|>erl-enced make money. Sample mailed, Circulars free. Cnsegreen WITg Co., 5d Victoria Street,
Toronto.
«EOBwKTUWN, ONT
Tornadoes are more numerous during pe I on we w,nt* ^old ^1®* l^e ^*slt
Hod. of violent solar agitation. The number	*¦ ******1	*"* .
and violence of tornadoes are directly proper- My longiugg»/f behind was oast Honed to the number and vioUn » of solar . Where fldweiy meadows lay, disturbances. Obeervatione made during the And brooding v er the vanished pait, pest winter and spring show that solar die* I * lo°^	oar sises way.
tarbanoee ate in some oases not marked by npets until a men h or two after the eruptions begin. Fifty-two days after the great storm
sâàS&SSSSÎS I	_
hurricane of March and 1888, whlsh wrecked several men-af war In the I Startled, I turned, and looked around : harbour of Apia This disturbance on the No Child's form met my gees ; euu was followed upon reappearance on May Bub one, low bending to the ground,
S9 and 30 by the flaode which wrecked Weary with weight of days, Johnstown, Pa., and drowned Williamsport, | Whose lips could utter forth no sound
Of thenkfuloeee or praise.
;
eve
ft ?
•• Farewell, farewell s 1 s en must go,*1 A voice said In my ear ;
“ The distant hills are white with enow ;
The Albert Toilet Soap Coy’f
Oatmeal Skin Soap
f)


MAKES THE HANDS SOFT AND THE COMPLEXION BEAUTIFUL. ¦¦ Bee tkai the Cer's
nervous
" Provident Life and Live SLoek law »
CHIEF OFFICE,
ROOM D, ARCADE, - TORONTO, CANADA
dlNlOBrOEATEDI
A Mutual Beuetit Aesotitatl
Ht am»* 4 »¦ the Heap aed
Wrap*»*
Pâ.
their storm motion oan be traced by counting Ah me 1 how ooeld I meet the King the twenty six day period. The solar die Who gave her to my oars ?
Serbs noee which caused severe and wMe- Loot were the gifts she oame to bring, spread storms during the first eight months And soiled nor raiment fair, of 1889 are now obscurs, spots being rarely Here, with the Old Year vanishing, Hat there Is evidence of noms activity | I con Id bet kneel In prayer, at the seat of the disturbances. Whenever violent action le resumed our atmosphere will he vexed Ij proportion to the violence on the sun.
BORROWERS
Lcnoif,
Books sent free sealed.
sod houwi properly yielding 7. 8. end 11' % to inrestore and ICO per cent to HPKCOLATOBVH^B
LID l%VEMTIIEST-Bv paying t# 8» abort
Awocmtiou ONE OEM PER DAT. » person aged ty-two, and and two oe"t* per day a person aged
__-four can weeure Five Dollar# per week while
disabled through tick nee# or accident, also for two and three cents per day, persons aged at ar secure for the r dep«ndanl. Five Hundred
n event ol death.	. . ___
LIVE RTSCK OWN EES can provide agaloMkes by death tiisoogh disease or accident of their stoea. at eawy rates. Those interested send for prospect etc. Reliable Agence wanted In unrepreeeu Meta
HXAMT D16LA81,
the symptoms of which are faint spells, pur-—[Chambers's Journal I P*® Ups, numbness, palpitation, skip boats,
.	____ I hot flashes, rush of blood to the head, dull
gEMEEEEEMEE pain In the heart with beats strong, rapid and
Irregular, the second heart beat quicker than first, pain about the breast bone, etc., oan positively be cured. No cure, no pay. Send for book. Address M. V, Lübok, 50 Front Street East, Toronto, Ont.
Do Dm»
KERB A KLEIBER,
U UNVILLI P. KlSISBB
The Dnmstiok.
J. L ATI mix Kerb.
4 King fttreel East, Toronto.
Sacceeeoreto A. K Wokler*C\ Offlw established
1879 by Mr. 8 H. Janet.
increase In populatlin Toronto 1889 over 1889 (awes-
tor's returns), 20 380.
the
B hold my rotund wealth of mwat. With all IU j aloes, rich and sweet 1 How firm, how solid, are my parts» And how 1 go straight to the hearts Of children, with distended jaws,
In wait to hide me in their maws.
lad Better Take Her Feet With Her-
West Side oh arch Is In process of renovation and the pastor Is engaged in raising funds to psy the expense. Oae means the pastor takes for that purpose is to call on hie parishioners and ask subeorlptio the good man approached the front door of a parishioner's house, rang the boll, the door opened and a little girl appeared.
Pastor—14 Good afternoon, my child. Is your mother at home t“
Little Girl—1H No, sir; mamma Is down
WHIIAW JOSES. Msntyior Director.
The wheels of matrimonial life run more smoothly where ther. Is a little juven Us.
SURBXit
CURB.»
In one case
Ah I how I love to lie in stats Up cm the table, while you wait With eager eyes and teeth that burn, Until It comes to be your turn.
How crisp mv skin, oh I bow brown. And how I tickle going down ;
, thon, my bone, on 1 what delight, To pick It till It's clean and whits.
A. P 484
TEN POUNDS
VO VS9 ÿfttTyS
ssS"SÜEI:i^^5
And
M
114
Pastor—" Will she be bank soon ? '
Little Girl—“I—I geese so."
Pastor—" Thon I will come In and wait a few minâtes."
Pastor eaters and takes s seat in the lor. Being desirous of knowing what of house his people provide for their families, the clergyman looked about him, and soon discovered a pair of test protruding from under a curtain. A little further optical Investigation satisfied him that the feet nged to the litt 11 girl’s mother. By and by the child appeared again and said that ¦he thought her mamma would not return for an hour or two. M Well,” says the pastor " I will not wait ; but, my child, be 0f kind enough to tell your mother the next time she goes down town to take her fee with her
T.
How would you like, on Chr letmae day, To tramp till noon and thon, well say,
To oome back horns, well almost starved, And find ms waiting, nloely carved ? Between your finger and your thumb
m, yum, yum 1
UJTWO WEEKS
If THINK OF IT I
NOTES for BIBLE STUDY
32 PAGE MONTHLY. ONLY 36 CENTS PER YEAR.
H
Ki
You hold me up, thus 1 tickle every nerve, I thrill Your stomachs, and I fill the bill, And with all men 1 nothing lack— In fact, I have the inside track I
As a Flesh Producer there can be me questiem but that
. IF. S. C. E.
WORKERS
SHOULD CAREFULLY READ
SCOTT’S
EMULSION
S. 8. TEflCflER
SHOULD
afotes for
J* Biblg Study
Memory Doctor Wanted.
" Are you the memory doctor ?" r—" lama profeoeor of the soisnoe
FOR #
Caller—
afotes for
J' Biblç Study
Prof
19
Its pages on the Weekly Study arc full and fresh.
•• Yes, I know ; you fix up memorise,1 •• In common {ir anoe. y "
41 That's what 1 neard. Well I want my memory doctored.’
•• That Is very easily dons. All yea have to do is to adopt my system and In a little while you will get so that you oan remember anything at alL"
" That Isn’t what I wank. I want my memory fixed ae I can't remember anyth !np. I have been called at a witness la a bwdle trial."-[New York Wseklv.
Of Pan Cod Liter Oil md Hipophosplltes
Of Lime and Soda is without a rival. Many have
lrirdnac$?,Yd B isy by tho ?
CONSUMPTION, I
SCROFULA, BRONCHITIS, COUGHS AND j COLDS. AND ALL FORMS OF WASTING DISEASES. AS PALATABLE AS MILK. J
Issuiss weds ky Scott ft Bowse. Belleville. Sslmonj
.......... — ~n
2STOTES
LOT*.
The night hu » thoutnad eyw,
And ihe d»r hot one j Yet the light of Ihe bright world die# With the dying
FOR
BIBLE STUDY
Wl
mr
The Best Publication Extant for
II

;
BIBCÇ STUDENTS
Tel Ihe light ol e wheta life dlee
SBMUSSÆ*'
A Lsrpe Estate.
ToiolIo
A bread land Is thii in which we Hvu,
while Insane, bet the Canadians wen t torn despair. Wherever there is humanity there hint loose to kill somebody else. Ho will U, offering; wherever there le et frying he shut op Joel ae tightly as U hie head g^ere la the beet field for this great was level, end given the remainder of hie Remedy. Consumption ( wbleh Ufa to *' think it over" and get ready to die. eorfnis)# yields to It, if employed in me Oar climate la different, yon knew.	| early stages of the disease ; Chirnio Nasal
Catarrh, yields to it ; Kidney diseases, yield to it ! If you want the best
of the blood,
PARENTS
PASTORS
WILL FIND IN
WILL FIND
t
otes for Biblg Study
n
hfotes for
j* BibleStudy
V
rniiCIBKS can make money during vacation 1 by oan rasai ng tor one or more of our fast soiling Book* and Bibles, especially History of Canada, by W. H. Wlihroy, D I> , latest and best edition ever published prices illustrated Publiât#- -
r*i .%
iHUL.
An invaluable help in preparing for Preaching, or Week Evening Services.
| Only 80c. per yesr. __________________________
Send for Sample Copy to A. G. WATSON, Manager, Toronto Willard. Tract Depository, cor. Yonge & Temperance Sts., Toronto, Canada.
A GREAT HELP IN
low, terms liberal
Write for WM. BRIGGS,
circular* and
Family Devotions

'
mORIMu CiriNO SCHOOL. Scientific and | reliable systems taught, whereby rtylleh, perfect fitter garments are produce L Send for circular. 8. CORRIGAN, Prop., 4 Adelaide St want
*ieip!6e
Bek# him • oup of oeffee—all he could take | man for a loan. A J JJ SSn ol<£Tfo«od It w-2 30*.-
i
S THOUSANDS OF BOTTLES I GIVEN AWAY YEARLY.
When I say Cure I do not mean merely to stop them for-a time, and then have them return again. I MEAN A ft A DICALC U RK. I have made the disease of Fite* Epilepsy or Falling Sickness a life-long study. I warrant my remedy to Cure the worst cases* Because others have failed Is no reason for not now receiving s cure. Send at once for a treatise and a Free Bottle of my Infallible Remedy. Give l x
It costs you nothing for a trial, and it will cure you. AcVHe i eh Office, ISO WEST ADELAIDE STREET, TORONTO.
I CURE FITS
ASTHMA ÇAjhjJSL
any one affliotsd. Das. TAFT BROS., Rochester, N Y
have
For Constipation, 81ok or Bilious Headache, use Dr. Pleroe’e Pallets, or Anti bilious • I Granules : Purely Vegetable and perfectly harmless. One a dose.
The builder of obelisks warn paid by the column.
AAA OuOkntes I sure cure for long-Il 11 II standing Coughs, Colds, etc. Atk
u,u.U li-Fo?
*
rpress and
a HOOT*
Post Office.
Truthful*
-s&asaMfc*.
S —I
„	.	.	I dlMMM psealUr to the ferrule ml The
The Leerned 8ociet.ee	on]y remedy for woman', peculiar 111», sold
rh,nneh .heir member, have teettoed to the by druggiito, under a positive guaranty, to maMlBoarr of Patnarn’. PUnlem Corn gfTe mttfaodon. 8m guaranty on wr»pp.r P*** ter It proTokoo no line ol d.maroa „f bottle. Thle guarantee ha* been faithfully K wearing alike the good will of the carried out for many yean by the proprie rTjklat and the meet hnmble, and with strict tore. toUftlallty, remoring with r^nriorienty R!o# m introduced into Korop, by the he corn, of ewh. Try Potnam a Corn Bz- garaouii. It I» Introdooed Into the Chinee.
with chop sticks.
and TUMOR Special! at Pri vale Hoepltal. No knifs. Bx>k free.
O.H.McMICHAEL. M.D, Niagara St, buffalo, N Y
Cancer
LS.
STANDARD CHOPPING USES BEST FRENCH BURR^Ti MILLSTONES Æ gg/
WEST GRINDER INTHf ( AJj^F i
JjSEPH MMDAUCH WRITES FROM MORRISONP.Q
Nov, 16th,
Now th it I have purchased from you one of year Sanlard French BuiFChoppinr Mille, turning la II ae part payment my Iron G rinder, I have objection to tell you that the plate# ueed In the Iro# Grinder ooet 92.00, and latterly but $1 00 per pUr. I used over $60.00 worth last wmfcr. Occasionally a plate would last a week, but eometinars not over two or three hours.
SAUSAGE rSx»
Orders filled for and desired quantity. Wilts for price
JAMES PARK & SON,
41 to 47 SX Lawrence Market, Toronto, Ont
KâTElAS in noeieu
i

JttD > J
¦aS.
scurcw
STONES WILL LAST A LITE TIME .
LIVE MBN
¦¦¦	WANTED
_ „ Hardy, Home-grown FRUIT TREES.
Price* low. Good pay and steady work. Free outfit.
The price cf the Mill was 165.00, muob ohea
J
that yours, hot In the end It was a very much dearer Mill: I am satisfied that Iron Grinders are only
H

K
(o
*
To

of Choppi 'g to do for their own
L
I
THE D W. BEADLE NURSERY COMPANY, LTD
fit Catharine*. OmL
J C3MEÀU. MAN WAKI, QUE.. WRITES :
A Happy Transi tien.
After five years' suffering from Jyipepia PH	. my wife got cored In one month by the frw
z*ÆMfSÊÊÊ
“ Impoeelble to overrate the value of So. Leon," e»y physicians.
5S53ESSS««
I
O


r I would feel Inoliowd to apologise for not writ!,* sooner hao I not been too busy, and my desire to give the 20 inch Standard Mill a fair trial before writing.
— TH1 —
Cheapest and
an
20
i
•Nch
happy to state that I an entirely ea Mill—It ie doing eplindld work.
ssÿ
In America to buy
Band and Mueioal
Teetrumenle,
FOR SALK.
Two No. 8 Iron Grinders at $16.00 each. Threat No llroa Tares Hi.t Iru 0 talers a) $3j,0) ea?h
plates.
Music, Ac.
E.W.Ck-BBAIITFOHD CANADA
Add roe, WHALEY, BOYCE A CO , 11$ Tenge Street, Tereete. Send for Catalogue.
„nd similar trades sre beet destroy them through u furnace.
boiling
•d by P“^°*
r.
(
\
»
###PAGE###8###



}
Km mesa will Ixt In id lenijK»raiily btiaidv of her liimtmiid.
LOCAL 4* 0 EXE HAL
i

3
lu the cuuiiti of hin speech on the Address in the Legislature lust <date>Friday</date>, Mr. Tail Ion gave as a reason why the government uf which he was then a member did
Tlie death of the Empress was aimouil- \ oed to the people by the lowering of the I Imperial stimasrd over the ijaIso*. The __
Kui press passed away prsqeful'y, surround
TRY THEM.
ARE THE BEST.
Hot accept the (larneau motion, condemn» in* the Dominion Government for Hilda oxecution, that it was a question of federal policy with which they had no right to in
Mr. Lussier, M P. 1\, remarked 11 tilted, that such refusal resulted to the death of the Ross Tallinn ministry, t<. vh ch Mr Tallinn replied it was " better to die well than live had.
ml by all her relatives and her much at tached attendants. A* the end came the mourners knelt around the bed and the court chaplain offered a prayer and then blessed the remains. Emperor William and the Km press soon after left the chamber.
The Empress Augusta suffered from influenza for three days, when pneumonia was developed. Her body is laid upon an Regarding Ottawa County, the Quebec open couch, and is shrouded with a white Government have decided to appeal from mantle. On her right hand is laid a spray the decision unseatirg Mr. Rochon, so of lily of the valley. Her head rep that he may retain his sent during the upon white pillows and her face is wrap session if he recovers sufficiently to be ped around with a covering of white lace, able to go down to Quebec. As this is The absolute peace and repose of her the last session, it was deemed unneees- beautiful, classical face is like that of a nary to go through the ordeal of a bye perfect statue.
election in such a large county. Friends	—--------------
of the g .venucut state that it will have Senator Clemow, on being asked if he much difficulty in inducing Mr. Rochon intended to take setion in regard to the to again run, as he is sick of \ olitio* and §gwdust nuisance at the forthcoming jwu lia* an is to retire. Mr. Msgor, advocate, of mentary session, promptly replied that Hull, and Mr. Devlin, of Aylmer, are he would. “ I shall move, ’ said he. “ for pointed to as government candidates if repmts on the matter. When 1 get the county is divided.	further information 1 shall be able to act.
_	_	%. ,x , The city council ought to take the matter
Father Libelle has started from Quebec up| l>ut they are afraid to do it. They for France and Belgium with a view lose- thi||k the city is dependent upon lumber cure an emigration of first-class practical ,„uu and that if they do anything the farmers. With reference to the Rev. De jHtt„r <lo ll(ll approve of the city will suf-puty Minister of agriculture it is stated fer That's all bosh. Even if the lumber Archbishop Fabre ha* signified his wish, if men did leave there would be plenty to Hot his command, that the rev. cure should takj ^eir place and paya fee. The luium to his parish of St. Jerome and water power would be very valuable for give up hi* position in the state’s ser- co(ton All<| woollen mills which would vice, but Mr. Mercier ap;waled to the employ labor.*'
Dope, stating that he will require the service of Monsgr. Lahel'e to continue hi* work on behalf of c» don nation. The Pope acquiesced in the wishes of the Premier, and the cure was allowed to remain in office.
frtttws. Jnnr i*th. 1S*T
lerfere.
SAME RIVAIS
Extensive
I
1
i’
)
SHAVTILLS, QUE.,
Shop-Opposite J. J Turner's Harness Shoj
I3V»
O
The public may rely on getting a first-clan*

job
A Call Solicited.
Shaw ville, Aug. ft, 1W.
House
Furnishing
Goods
NOW GOING- ON AT
Bryson, Graham
& Co’s,
Harness
TO THE FRONT.
o
A. W. N. BELL,
Main Street • • Qeyon,
Respectfully intimât** to all requiring Herne** of any klutl, ih*i their I ate rests cau best tie nerved by purchasing from him.
The Best Material.
A row ia brewing over a hill which Mr. Pilon, th* member for IUg<t n the Qti • bee legislature, has prejwred. He want* t > grrrymander Sheflbrd County by de-• aching twenty five lots from it to add to Bagot. It appears that the adjoining uiu nicipaîity in Bagot is building a Catholic church which promises to l>e too cxpoii-Mre fur them and they want a slice «oit of Sh« ff rd to help bear the burden. The residents in the required »f> Shvttotd lots are mostly Protestants, and they have ap oealed to the member for Shetturd, Dr. D« (îroshois. to prevent the gerrymander, which Dr DeGmabois says he will do
coats.
Skilful Workmanship.
Prices always Right.
146,148,150,152 and and 154 Sparks St. Ottawa.
Quyon, Oct. 17IU Isa».
Several important hills are to he introduced in the Quebec Legislature tins session by Dr. de Grosbo’c, the principal of which is one to hold railway companies responsible tor the pay i f their laborers when contractors or sub-contractors make default. The companies will be obliged to make sure that the laborers are paid their wages before paying the contractu*# the money due them. Another is to en- ..	.. .	.
able farmers to sell off their goods (except I political for sja'v illative purposes) without employ -	"
in g a licensed auctioneer and paying ate-. lion fee*. Another is to relieve secretary-treasurers of municipalities from ) sweating the va nation rolls are Correct, [ for the secretary-treasurer has nothing to j do with making up these rolls, and cotise-1 quently cannot ho expected to certify that, they are correct. Another is a bill to in-1 corporate a company to build a railway |
Law renew’He., in Sheff rd county, to L ,
Avenir, a distance of 40 miles.	!
RATIONAL
C0LLB8E, OTTAWA, ONT,
SASH I DOOR FACTORY,
SHAW VILLE, QUE.
at
Corner Hparka «ml O Von nor street.
POSITIVELY lh< mi nt thorough course, special attention U» tVumiTishlp wlihootex-t : a charge. A «INcmmt of V» perv-nt. on a! tuition foes to ladles. Catrloguvn liev. Send lor ont
In returning thanks to the public generally for the very liberal patronage bestowed upon us, wo would state that wo i have on hand a large stock of
SASHES,
SEASON OF 1889-90.
Address C? II* McCAItOAH. Principal
SLEIGHS !
DOORS,
C. B. DRAPER,
Jeweler
DOOR FRAMES,
NEUL POSTS,
BANNISTERS,
and everything required iu WOOD FINISHING,
HAND RAILINGS,
SLEIGHS !
ANO^
Optician,
D)&th of the A?«4 D:W&»er Zaires The undersigned begs to Inform the inhab-
Ar of derm^nv.	Hants of Shaw ville and aurroundliig cntui-
^	***	try that he In BOV preparing to supply the
Beilin, Jmiiinry 7.— Tim Powayor Em- I public during the coinlug winter .ea.on, with
press Augusts died here to-day nt 4 uO o'-1 al1 ttlnd“ of eielgbs.__
clock p. mi. The Empress who was suffer part|es may re|y OH getting ing from influenza had a relapse to day and her re#ptr*lion became very difficult.
At 2 p. iu. the Emperoi and Em pres • and shell two eldest sons. Crown Prince
William and Prince Frederick, and the | ORDERS EXECUTED PROMPTLY Grand Duke and Grand Duchess of Baden, in law and daughter respectively ot Dowager Empress, were at her bedside.
Count Von Moltke left her jialace at noon.
He was much affected at lier condition.
A large crowd assembled in Voter der Linden he'ore the palace and much aym-path y was shown.
When the Kaiser was summoned at 6 o'clock this morning, the Empress kisstd him fondly. The Empress became unconscious several times to-day. Shortly before her death she was perfectly
7ioU,_a"d r,eco*niMd f ‘hti .Iv^' fa“V I VJOTICK t, h,r,h,7^Tn by me. the under-ily. The street are already draped with	e|gnHd. to all persons Indebted tome by
mourning. The Court festivities, which Hook A ornant, Note, or otherwise, to settle had been resumed upon the expiration ofl'h"	tortUnb st my offlro' end ,eve
the mourning for Emperor Frederick, are
now abandoned. The remains of the ex-1 Hhawvllle 18th Dec. 1K*9
SCROLL SAWING IN EVERY VARIETY and DESIGN.
Umber dressed at reasonable rates. All kinds of Cnstom Work solicited.
Main St., Shawville, P.Q.
Watches, Clacks Jk Jewelry repaired. Coin Jewelry made to Order.
No. I material, and the very I One year guarantee given With all work.
best of workmanship.
:o
NOTICE.
AGENT KOB THE
Sometime ago we added to our Factory a Patterson GRINDER for reducing oats to provender. This will be found a great convenience to the farming community. Any quantity of grain ground on the shortest notice.
Celebrated “B LiDRANCE” Spectacles
AND EYEGLASSES
Special Attention given to Repairs
September 12.10*».
Boil
House Building a Specialty.
ROBT. McCREDIE & SONS.
IMPORTANT.
Agent fur the Gananoque Carriage* and Cutters.
A CALL SOLICITED.
J. BECKETT, Jr. |	er Hor,e' or
CHITTY * CO., OTTAWA,
who bold
Regular Auction Sales of Stock
Fortnightly.
FftOFKISTOKS.
akawville. Oet.lS
WHERE TO BUY IT
Shaw ville, Oct. 1,188»
Notice.
con-

As the Fall weather sets in it is the ambition of every young man (and many an old man too) to provide himself with a new suit. This leads to thequestion : “ * here is he to buy ?” Nothing more simple to answer.
We also well Real Estate. If you want to buy or sell a farm give os a call.
We have an Employment Bureau where men, women and girls can be suited with respectable places.
costs. Collections ronet ho made anyhow
HUGH MATH EBON
CHITTY «6 CO.,
4, Elgin street, • - - Ottawa.
Bepl. *#,'**.
JUST READ THIS.
TAILORING EMPORIUM
SHAWVILLB, - - - QUE.
I r
i u
*
510£ SUSSEX STREET, OTTAWA.
Keeps one of the largest stocks of cloths that is to be found
ill the city. Ho cannot fail to SUIT you, ns his goods
comprise every grade of manufacture, style and pattern.
Prices to suit every one.
HATS, SHIRTS, TIES, UNDERWEAR, HOISERY.
er
QUAND
I 09
02
y
r. «
I
S3 °

E
L
c V
c r * -•
% <R
I 2
0

Of all kinds of Tweeds, Trowser-ings, Worsteds and Overcoatings.

« J
BE SURE AND CALL WHEN IN TOWN.
N
Ï ® 5
' 1
Ml
o’» CO
i

McOOLL BEOS. Sc 00.
I desire to clear out my present large assortment during the Holiday season so as to be prepared to put in a first-class stock for spring, early. In order to do so, I have marked down all Tweeds twenty per cent, and will continue the sale at these prices
5
THE LEADING OIL MERCHANTS of CANADA
»
¦
are still pleasing the public with oils. Why use an oil that will injure your machinery when you can get the celebrated
il?
i i 1 :
c
5
2=1 gri
S1
FOR 30 DAYS BEGINNING DECEMBER 1st.
¦ ¦ - ¦ ¦ —
cc
99
?
il
K*
i
All part!*»* deni ring nothin* nhould call and be convinced that tble advertisement la correct before puiohaalng elsewhere.
HPBC1ALTIRH
Cylinder, Lardine, Wool, Eureka, Spindle, Bolt-Cutting,
Solar,	Marnes*,
Romemtor ths Place •• Star Tailoring Emporium,
X1I.1 STREET, SHAWVILLE.
f o
Ft
MANUFACTURERS, McCOLL BROS. & Co., TORONTO.
O
ill
3»
o-
;
G. H. MOORE, PROPRIETOR.

For sale by all dealers throughout the Dominion,
n

#


