Equity issue,Day,Description,Section,Type,
1895-01-03,21-Dec,  A very successful entertainment was held in <LOCATION>Stark</LOCATION>'s school house on the evening of the 21st. The program consisted of dialogue  recitations and singing. ,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,event,
1895-01-03, Monday, Public notice is hereby given to all owners of real estate and resident house holders of the municipality of the village of <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> that a meeting of the municipal electors will be held in the council Hall on Monday the 14th day of January 1895 at the hour of ten o'clock in the forenoon to proceed with the election of three councillors in the room and stead of <PERSON>James Prendergast Thos</PERSON>. <PERSON>Dale</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Lester</PERSON> whose term of office has expired., public notice,event,
1895-01-03, Monday, Public notice is hereby that a public meeting of the proprietors of real estate and resident house holders of this municipality  that a meeting of the municipal electors will be held in the town hall in the village of one thousand eight hundred and nintety-five at the hour of ten o'clock in the morning to proceed with the election of two councillors in the room and stead of <PERSON>Jphn Murray</PERSON> and <PERSON>James Wilson</PERSON> whose terms of office have expired., public notice,event,
1895-01-03, Monday, three hundred Cedars (300) delivered at the <LOCATION>Town Hall Shawville</LOCATION> or on the repspective spots where they may be wanted. Tenders will be revieved up to 10 a.m. of the 1st Monday in January 1895 for the whole or any part thereof, public notice,event,
1895-01-03,Christmas,  The members of the Baptist church showed their appreciation of the services of their worthy pastor Rev. <PERSON>J. Medcof</PERSON> by presenting him with a handsome fur coat on the afternoon of Christmas day. The ladies of the congregation went well provided with good things to which all did ample justice. Mr. <PERSON>Medcof</PERSON> was com pletely taken by surprise and replied in a feeling manner.,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,church,
1895-01-03,Christmas,Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Ed</PERSON>. <PERSON>Graham</PERSON> entertained quite a number of invited guests Xmas night.,Elmside notes,event,
1895-01-03,Christmas,The members of <ORGANIZATION>Prospect Lodge</ORGANIZATION> invited the <LOCATION>Victoria Lodge</LOCATION> to attend their meeting on Christmas night.,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,event,
1895-01-03,n/a, Miss <PERSON>Holton</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Belleville</LOCATION> is spending a  few days here the guest of Miss <PERSON>McAllister</PERSON>, <LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION>,arrival,
1895-01-03,Friday,<PERSON>Miss L. Black</PERSON> left off school on Friday for two month's holidays and is visiting at Mrs. <PERSON>John Bradley</PERSON>'s.,<LOCATION>Greer Mount</LOCATION> notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,Friday,  Mr. <PERSON>John R. Young</PERSON> returned home Friday evening from the Hospital in <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> very little improved but seems better since.,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,Friday, Mr. <PERSON>Andrew Grant</PERSON> arrived home on Friday night accompanied my Miss <PERSON>J. McPherson</PERSON> of Almonte., Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,Monday,  Mr. <PERSON>William Shaw</PERSON> has removed his household effects to <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> where he intends residing for the future.,Local and general,departure,
1895-01-03,Monday, Public notice is hereby given that it is the intention of the <ORGANIZATION>Municipal Council</ORGANIZATION> of the Township of <LOCATION>Bristol</LOCATION> to examine and honologate at its sittings in the townhall on Monday the 7th day of January 1895 at the hour of ten in the forenoon the Proces Verbal of the old Ragged CHute Road ordered by resolution of the <ORGANIZATION>Council</ORGANIZATION> on Monday the 5th day of November 1894., public notice,event,
1895-01-03,Monday,A very pleasant time was spent at the home of Mr. <PERSON>Richard Hynes</PERSON> on Monday evening last. The guests began to assemble about 7 o'clock and continued coming until a goodly number were present. Games of all kinds were indulged in; music and singing was also a favourite passtime of the evening whilst others seem to enjoy very much the sweet tones of the hand-organ. As the New Year was ushering in  the guests were doing justice to a large variety of choice refreshments. Supper being ended wishes for a bright and happy new year retired to their respective homes went on for a short time. Then the young folks having recieved and given many good , <PERSON>Clarendon</PERSON> front notes,event, 
1895-01-03,Monday, The remains of the late widow <PERSON>Sinclair</PERSON> were interred in the Anglican burial ground here on Monday, Local and General,death,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>Alex Bell</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Sturgeon Falls Ont</ORGANIZATION>. Are spending the holidays with friends in <LOCATION>N.O.</LOCATION> and Quyon.,North Onslow notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>John Turner</PERSON> left again last week for the west. ,North Onslow notes,departure,
1895-01-03,n/a,At <PERSON>M. Kane</PERSON>'s has arrived a boy visitor whom I hear intends to stay.,North Onslow notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Men and teams are leaving for the woods daily.,North Onslow notes,departure,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>P. Kane</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Hazelhurst Wis</LOCATION>. Arrived home last week and intends remaining for the winter months.,North Onslow notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,"Mr. <PERSON>F. Hearty</PERSON> spent the holidays with friends in <PERSON>Vinton</PERSON>. Welcome back F. how ""she"" missed you.",North Onslow notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,  Mr. <PERSON>J.H. Brownlee</PERSON> wishes to announce that the Shawville skating rink is now running and will be open every week night (except Fridays) weather permitting during the season. A carnival will be held in the near future regarding which posters will be issued in a day or two.,Local and General,event,
1895-01-03,n/a,Revival meetings are going on here now at <LOCATION>Craig</LOCATION>'s <LOCATION>Church.</LOCATION>,<LOCATION>Greer Mount</LOCATION> notes,church,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Maggie Martin</PERSON> is visiting at Mrs. <PERSON>J. Bradley</PERSON>'s.,<LOCATION>Greer Mount</LOCATION> notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a, <PERSON>S. A. McKay</PERSON> BCL. NOTARY PUBLIC. Clerk of the Magistrates COurt at <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION>. Agent for the Credit Founder Franco Canadian. Money to lend on easy terms. Will be in <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> from Monday till Friday of each week. Will visit <LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION> the second Tuesday of each month.,advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,  Miss <PERSON>Lyla McLean</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Eardley</LOCATION> has been a guest of Miss <PERSON>Lorena Hodgins</PERSON> for the last few days.,Local and general,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Carey</PERSON> of the <LOCATION>Fort</LOCATION> is spending the holidays at Mr. <PERSON>Robert Smart</PERSON>'s.,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,An amateur fox hunt took place at <LOCATION>Elmside</LOCATION>,<LOCATION>Bristol</LOCATION> notes,event,
1895-01-03,n/a,The annual congregational meeting of the Presbyterian church was held on Friday evening 28th and notwithstanding the severity of the weather was well attended,<LOCATION>Bristol</LOCATION> notes,church,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mrs. <PERSON>E. Graham</PERSON> gave a six o'clock dinner to a number of her many friends,<LOCATION>Bristol</LOCATION> notes,event,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>C. Dunkerley</PERSON> late principal of the academy is visiting her acquaintances here this week,Local and General,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>A. Grimes</PERSON> and bride of <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> are the guests of Mr. <PERSON>B. Smart</PERSON>,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>E. L. McJanet</PERSON> has gone to spend the holidays with her parents.,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,departure,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Amelia Smart</PERSON> is home for the holidays,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,  The Ven. <PERSON>Archdeacon Naylor</PERSON> has been holding a series of cottage meetings which are well attended and appreciated.,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,church,
1895-01-03,n/a,<PERSON>Mrs Wm. Lochart</PERSON> and two daughters from <LOCATION>Edmonton</LOCATION> are visiting friends here.,<PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>F. S. Roy</PERSON> is spending a few days at home.,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Annie</PERSON> and <PERSON>Agnes Murray</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>Letts</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Calumet Island</LOCATION> also mr. <PERSON>Larivee</PERSON> of <PERSON>Arnprior</PERSON> spent New Year with Mr. <PERSON>Andrew Grant.</PERSON>,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>Syvanus Richards</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Arnprior</LOCATION> is visiting friends here at the present.,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Grace McKechnie</PERSON> spent a few days in <LOCATION>Elmside</LOCATION> last week.,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,A few of our sportsmen tried to make Xmas a little exciting by organizing a fox hunt. ,Elmside notes,event,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>Alex Stewart</PERSON> returned home a few days ago and intends remaining with us.,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Jessie McPherson</PERSON> of <PERSON>Almonte</PERSON> is visiting friends here,<PERSON>Elmside</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>W. Finlan</PERSON> and sister Miss <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> spent a few days in <LOCATION>Renfrew</LOCATION> last week. The Misses <PERSON>Finlan</PERSON> are home for their holidays.,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>Eddie Larivee</PERSON> just landed in town to spend <LOCATION>New Year.</LOCATION>,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>S. Richard</PERSON> and daughter Miss <PERSON>Jennie May</PERSON> are visiting friends at <LOCATION>Elmside.</LOCATION>,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,Mrs. <PERSON>Ale McDonald</PERSON> and daughter Miss <PERSON>Mabel</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Pembroke</LOCATION> is visiting her father Mr. <PERSON>R. Campbell</PERSON>,Elmside notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a,  Mr. <PERSON>J.Y. Caldwell</PERSON> manager of <ORGANIZATION>W.C. Gibson</ORGANIZATION>'s biscuit factory was presented with a gold headed cane by the employes of the above named firm last week, <PERSON>Elmside</PERSON> notes,event,
1895-01-03,n/a,  Miss <PERSON>Grace McKechnie</PERSON> principal of Thurso public school Miss MacIntosh teacher of no. 8 school <PERSON>Clarendon</PERSON> were visiting at Mr <PERSON>James Armstrong</PERSON>'s last week., <PERSON>Clarendon</PERSON> front notes,arrival,
1895-01-03,n/a, Parties are all the rage around here just now: On Xmas night Mr. <PERSON>Edward Graham</PERSON> welcomes the juvenile host and gave a party. Saturday night saw one at Mr. <PERSON>Andrew Grant</PERSON>'s. Monday night we took possession of Mr. <PERSON>McKechnie</PERSON>'s house and paid our last respects to the old year by seeing it out. Tuesday night we are billed for Mr. <PERSON>William Graham</PERSON>'s and Wednesday night wind up at Mr. <PERSON>Lothian</PERSON>'s to give <PERSON>George</PERSON> a lively send off before he returns to <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> to resume his studies., Elmside notes,event,
1895-01-03,New Year's,A watch service was held in the Methodist church here on New Year's eve.,Local and General,church,
1895-01-03,New Year's,  <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> and <PERSON>Billy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Artie</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harry of Quio</PERSON> put up for an hour or so in the village whilst on their way to the concert at <PERSON>Bryson</PERSON> on New Year's.,Local and general,arrival,
1895-01-03,New Year's,  There was a very large attendance at the social held at the parsonage on New Year night. A good program of music and addresses by the <PERSON>Archdeacon</PERSON> and Rev. <PERSON>A. Elliott</PERSON> and Mr. <PERSON>T.J. Wilson</PERSON> embraced the chief features of the evening's entertainment.,Local and general,event,
1895-01-03,New Year's,  The concert at <LOCATION>Bryson</LOCATION> on New Year night is reported to have been a very successful affair. The hall was well filled and the program  supplied by local talent strongly reinforced by a contingent of <LOCATION>Pembroke</LOCATION> amateurs was well selected and excellently rendered throughout. The net receipts amounted to $35.,Local and general,event,
1895-01-03,New Year's,  Several of our young people attended the concert at <LOCATION>Bryson</LOCATION> on New Year's night., <PERSON>Parkman</PERSON> notes,event,
1895-01-03,Saturday,  Father <PERSON>Dawson</PERSON> one of the best known and most respected priante in the <LOCATION>Ottawa Valley</LOCATION> died at <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> on Saturday aged 86 years.,Local and General,death,
1895-01-03,Saturday, Mr. <PERSON>R.W. Hodgins</PERSON> late teacher of the Model school spent Saturday in this village., <PERSON>Clarendon</PERSON> front notes,arrival, 
1895-01-03,Sunday,  Mr. <PERSON>W. G. Bradford</PERSON> of the Thorne Methodist circuit spent his Xmas holidays at <LOCATION>Listowel</LOCATION> Ont. The <ORGANIZATION>Listowel Banner</ORGANIZATION> states that our young friend had consented to conduct the services in the Baptist church there on Sunday 30th in the absence of the pastor.,Local and General,church,
1895-01-03,Sunday, Mr. <PERSON>Elliott</PERSON> of <PERSON>Haley</PERSON>'s station preached in Zion church on Sunday 30th.,Local and General,church,
1895-01-03,Thursday, ARTHUR McCONNELL Attourney at Law Main St. Hull Que will at request attend all courts in the district. All correspondence promptly answered. Will be at <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> first Thursday of each month, advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-03,Thursday,On Thursday evening last the annual installation of officers of the <ORGANIZATION>Pontiac Lodge No. 40 A. F. & A. M.</ORGANIZATION> took place in the <LOCATION>Masonic Hall</LOCATION> here,Local and General,event,
1895-01-03,Tuesday,  The daily mail between here and Otter Like began on Tuesday last with Mr. <PERSON>Samuel Howes</PERSON> as courier.,Local and general,event,
1895-01-03,n/a,  DENTISTRY DR. <PERSON>STACKHOUSE</PERSON> Sr. Dentist will visit the undermentioned places on the dates named: Quyon Tuesday Jan. 8th. Shawville Wednesday Jan 9th. Campbells Bay Thursday Jan 10th., advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-03,Wednesday,Mr. <PERSON>Henry Judd</PERSON> was joined in wedlock on Wednesday 19th to Miss <PERSON>Mary Ebert.</PERSON>,<LOCATION>Greer Mount</LOCATION> notes,event,
1895-01-03,Wednesday, <PERSON>Maurice Chevalier</PERSON> L.L.L. Advocate Bryson W SPECIAL ATTENTION GIVEN TO ALL COLLECTIONS. Visits Quyon on second and last Wednesday of very month. Will visit <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> on the first and third Wednesday of every month., advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-03,Wednesday, Dr. <PERSON>W.C. McGUIRE</PERSON> VETERINARY SURGEON Graduate of <ORGANIZATION>McGill University of Montreal Office</ORGANIZATION> -- 88 <ORGANIZATION>Lyon St. Ottawa Will</ORGANIZATION> visit <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> on the first and third Wednesday of every month, advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-03,Wednesday, Dr. <PERSON>W.C. McGUIRE</PERSON> VETERINARY SURGEON Graduate of <ORGANIZATION>McGill University of Montreal Office</ORGANIZATION> -- 88 <ORGANIZATION>Lyon St. Ottawa Will</ORGANIZATION> visit <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> on the first and third Wednesday of every month, advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-10,05-Jan,Diptheria has made its appearence in this locality proving fatal in one case - the seven year old daughter of Mr <PERSON>John A. Cameron</PERSON>, notes from <PERSON>Murell</PERSON>'s Settlement,death,
1895-01-10,21-Dec,a Xmas tree held here Dec 21st. The evening was favourable and the audience all that could be desired to make the entertainment a success. The proceeds amounted to $20 to be applied towards building a woodshed school, Local and General,event,
1895-01-10,27-Dec, At <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> on Dec. 27th the wife of Mr <PERSON>John M Hodgins</PERSON> of a son, local and general,birth,
1895-01-10, Monday, Public notice is hereby given to all owners of real estate and resident house holders of the municipality of the village of <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> that a meeting of the municipal electors will be held in the council Hall on Monday the 14th day of January 1895 at the hour of ten o'clock in the forenoon to proceed with the election of three councillors in the room and stead of <PERSON>James Prendergast Thos</PERSON>. <PERSON>Dale</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Lester</PERSON> whose term of office has expired., public notice,event,
1895-01-10, Monday, Public notice is hereby that a public meeting of the proprietors of real estate and resident house holders of this municipality  that a meeting of the municipal electors will be held in the town hall in the village of one thousand eight hundred and nintety-five at the hour of ten o'clock in the morning to proceed with the election of two councillors in the room and stead of <PERSON>Jphn Murray</PERSON> and <PERSON>James Wilson</PERSON> whose terms of office have expired., public notice,event,
1895-01-10,16-Dec,On the 16th inst in <LOCATION>Litchfield</LOCATION> school one of the lady members purpose giving a speech on the Patrons, Notes from <ORGANIZATION>Murell</ORGANIZATION>'s Settlement,event,
1895-01-10,Christmas, to the wife of Jas. <PERSON>L. Shaw</PERSON> on Dec. 25th '94 a daughter., local and general,birth,
1895-01-10,Friday,All the services will be held as usual except the Friday night services., Local and General,church,
1895-01-10,Friday,At 436 <PERSON>Maria St</PERSON> on the 4th inst to the wife of <PERSON>H.T Smith</PERSON> a daughter, local and general,birth,
1895-01-10,Friday,At fort coulonge on Friday Jan 4th to the wife of <PERSON>John Bryson M.P.</PERSON> of a daughter,local and general,birth,
1895-01-10,Friday,Mr. <PERSON>J.T. Pattison</PERSON> of the Advance is announced to preach in the Methodist church here on Sunday next, local and general,church,
1895-01-10,Friday,A grand carnival will be held in the skating rink here on Friday evening next. Admission adults 15 cents children 10 c. costumed skaters admitted free. Everybody welcome, local and general,event,
1895-01-10,Monday,  Mr. <PERSON>Borthwick</PERSON> was elected mayor of <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> on Monday over Mr. Cluff., Local and general,event,
1895-01-10,Monday,Miss <PERSON>Bella Armstrong</PERSON> of <PERSON>Ramsay</PERSON> aged 25 was killed in jumping from a moving train at <LOCATION>Almonte</LOCATION> station on Monday of last week, local and general,death,
1895-01-10,Monday, <PERSON>Willie Ringrose</PERSON> left last Monday for the woods. Who next?, Notes from <PERSON>Murell</PERSON>'s Settlement,departure,
1895-01-10,Monday, Minutes of a regular session of the municipal council of the village of <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> held on Monday the 18th of January 1895, <ORGANIZATION>Shawville Council Minutes</ORGANIZATION>,event,
1895-01-10,n/a,  Mr. <PERSON>B. McGrath</PERSON> school inspector was town on Monday and Tuesday last, local and general,arrival,
1895-01-10,n/a,Miss <PERSON>C. C. Wilson</PERSON> has left for <LOCATION>Carthage New York</LOCATION> where she intends visiting friends for some time,Local and general,departure,
1895-01-10,n/a,Mrs. <PERSON>H. Argue</PERSON> has gone to visit her daughter Mrs. Rev. <PERSON>Wm. Knox</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Addison Ont.</LOCATION>,Local and general,departure,
1895-01-10,n/a, at the Parsonage West shefford Que the wife of the Rev. <PERSON>S. A. mills</PERSON> of a son, local and general,birth,
1895-01-10,n/a,  Dr. <PERSON>W. C. McGuire D.V.S.</PERSON> has left for <LOCATION>Mattawa</LOCATION> where he intends practicing during the winter months. ,Local and General,departure,
1895-01-10,New Year's,The concert held in <LOCATION>Walsh's Hall Bryson</LOCATION> on New Years night proved quite a success, Local and General,event,
1895-01-10,New Year's, Mr. and Mrs. <PERSON>R. Cuthbertson</PERSON> spent New Year's day with their daughter Mrs. <PERSON>C. Stewart</PERSON>,Notes from <PERSON>Murell</PERSON>'s Settlement, arrival,
1895-01-10,Saturday,on Saturday morning Dec 29th Mr. <PERSON>Thomas G. Somerville</PERSON> an old resident of <PERSON>Fitzroy</PERSON> was found dead in his chair beside the kitchen fire, local and general,death,
1895-01-10,Sunday,Mr. <PERSON>J. T. Pattison</PERSON> of the Advance is announced to preach in the Methodist church here on Sunday next.,Local and general,church,
1895-01-10,Sunday,The Rev. <PERSON>W.C. Dilworth</PERSON> will conduct the service Sunday morning and the Rev. <PERSON>J. L. Flanain</PERSON> the evening., Local and General,church,
1895-01-10,Sunday,Mr. <PERSON>Wm. Wilson</PERSON> student conducted the service in the Methodist church on Sunday evening last, local and general,church,
1895-01-10,Thursday, <PERSON>Archdeacon Naylor</PERSON> leaves tomorrow (Thursday) morning for <LOCATION>Montreal</LOCATION> to attend committee meetings this week and the Synod of the Diocese next week. He will return the 18th or the 19th., Local and General,church,
1895-01-10,Thursday, Mr. <PERSON>J.H. Shaw</PERSON> began the removal of his stock into his magnificent new store on Thursday last., local and general,event,
1895-01-10,Tuesday, as provided for by the terms of the Dominion Electoral Franchise Act. The revision of the lists for this village and the municipality of <LOCATION>Clarendon</LOCATION> took place on Tuesday last., local and general,event,
1895-01-10,Tuesday,Mr. <PERSON>Alf McRae</PERSON>. left on Tuesday for <LOCATION>Belleville</LOCATION> where he intends taking a course in the business college there, local and general,departure,
1895-01-10,Tuesday, There will be offered for sale by public auction at the <LOCATION>Russell House Ottawa</LOCATION> on Tuesday the 11th day of March next 1895 at 3 o'clock P.M. the Pine Spruce and <ORGANIZATION>Tamarac Timber</ORGANIZATION>, advertisement,event,
1895-01-10,Wednesday,At <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> on Jan 2nd the wife of Dr. <PERSON>H. H. Knox</PERSON> a son, local and general,birth,
1895-01-10,Wednesday, Mr. <PERSON>Robert McKenney</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Onslow</LOCATION> agent for the <PERSON>Egan</PERSON> estate was in town on Wednesday last settling taxes and transacting other business for the estate of which he is the sole agent in the county, local and general,arrival,
1895-01-10,Wednesday,He intends however paying a professional visit to this village the second Wednesday of every month,Local and General,arrival,
1895-01-17,Friday, Several of the young people of <LOCATION>Portage du Fort</LOCATION> attended the Carnival here on Friday evening last., Local and General,arrival,
1895-01-17,Friday, The carnival held on Friday evening on the skating rink was only very slimly attended which was rather discouraging, Local and General,event,
1895-01-17,Friday, her remains were interred at <LOCATION>North Clarendon</LOCATION> on Friday a very large number of friends and acquaintances attending the obsequies, Local and General Death,death,
1895-01-17,Monday, <PERSON>Renfrew</PERSON> elected its first town council on Monday of last week as follows, Local and General,event,
1895-01-17,Monday, Mr. <PERSON>Campbell</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Dundas Ont</ORGANIZATION>. Grand Lecturer of the <ORGANIZATION>Canadian Order of Chosen Friends</ORGANIZATION> addressed a small audience here on Monday evening last in the interesys of the Order, Local and General,event,
1895-01-17,n/a, <PERSON>S. A. MCKAY</PERSON> BCL. NOTARY PUBLIC. Clerk of the Magistrates COurt at <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION>. Agent for the Credit Founder Franco Canadian. Money to lend on easy terms. Will be in <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> from Monday till Friday of each week. Will visit <LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION> the second Tuesday of each month., advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-17,n/a, <PERSON>S. A. MCKAY</PERSON> BCL. NOTARY PUBLIC. Clerk of the Magistrates COurt at <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION>. Agent for the Credit Founder Franco Canadian. Money to lend on easy terms. Will be in <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> from Monday till Friday of each week. Will visit <LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION> the second Tuesday of each month., advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-17,n/a,Mrs. <PERSON>Wm. Eades</PERSON> has gone on a visit to her daughter Mrs. <PERSON>Wm. Steele</PERSON>,<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,departure,
1895-01-17,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Annie Jones</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Eau Claire</ORGANIZATION> is the guest of Mrs. <PERSON>George Richardson</PERSON>,<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-17,n/a,Mr. <PERSON>Little</PERSON>'s are around again after being closed in on account of diphtheria,Clarendon Front Notes,event,
1895-01-17,New Year's, Quite a number of young folks gathered at the house of Mrs. <PERSON>T. Richardson</PERSON> on New Year's night and spent the evening in social amusements, <PERSON>Radford</PERSON> Notes,event,
1895-01-17,Saturday, Mrs. <PERSON>John Bradley</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Eardley</LOCATION> and son <LOCATION>Wellington</LOCATION> who have been visiting friends in this neighbourhood for the past week returned home on Saturday accompanied by Miss <PERSON>Annie Grant</PERSON>, <PERSON>Radford</PERSON> Notes,arrival,
1895-01-17,Saturday,  Mr. <PERSON>J. H. Brownlee</PERSON> proprietor of the Shawville skating rink wishes it to be / announced that he will give a carnival on Saturday night of this week to the boys and girls under 16 years of age. Admission to spectators over that age (except ticket holders who will be admitted free) will be 10 cents. The carnival will be open at 7 o'clock. Ice will be open to all skaters at half past 8 o'clock. It is hoped that a goodly number of the juvenile skaters of the village will avail themselves of this opportunity to appear in costume., Fun for the Youngsters,event,
1895-01-17,Sunday, In consequence of the illness of Rev. Mr. <PERSON>Dilworth</PERSON> that rev. gentleman was unable to conduct the service in <LOCATION>St. Paul</LOCATION>'s church on Sunday morning last as announced therefore none was held till evening when the Rev. <PERSON>J. L. Flanagan</PERSON> officiated., local and general,church,
1895-01-17,Thursday, ARTHUR McCONNELL Attourney at Law Main St. Hull Que will at request attend all courts in the district. All correspondence promptly answered. Will be at <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> first Thursday of each month, advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-17,Tuesday,Mr. <PERSON>Andy Farrell</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Otter Lake</LOCATION> payed a visit to <PERSON>Radford</PERSON> on Tuesday and returned Wednesday,<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-17,Wednesday, Dr. <PERSON>W.C. McGUIRE</PERSON> VETERINARY SURGEON Graduate of <ORGANIZATION>McGill University of Montreal Office</ORGANIZATION> -- 88 <ORGANIZATION>Lyon St. Ottawa Will</ORGANIZATION> visit <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> on the first and third Wednesday of every month, advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-17,Wednesday, the death of Mrs. <PERSON>Samuel Hamilton of Clarendon</PERSON> who breathed her last on Wednesday of last week,Local and General death,death,
1895-01-17,Wednesday, on Wednesday evening last Court <PERSON>Shawville I.O.F.</PERSON> was put upon what may be regarded as a fairly good working basis by the installation of a new staff of officers to transact the business of the current year, Local and General,event,
1895-01-17,Wednesday, Wednesday was also made memorable by the uniting in matrimony of Mr. <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> third son of Mr. <PERSON>Richard Dagg</PERSON> with Miss <PERSON>Jennie</PERSON> second daughter of the late <PERSON>John Sturgeon</PERSON> all of <LOCATION>Clarendon</LOCATION>, Clarendon Front Notes,event,
1895-01-31,n/a,  <LOCATION>Miss Fanny Hill</LOCATION> is spending a few days visiting her parents., <PERSON>Thornby</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-31, Tuesday, Dr. <PERSON>A. Lyon</PERSON> left on Tuesday to attend the annual communication of the <ORGANIZATION>Masonic Grand Lodge of Quebec</ORGANIZATION>, Local and General,departure,
1895-01-31, Tuesday, Mrs. <PERSON>John McTiernan</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Clarendon</LOCATION> passed away at two o'clock on Tuesday morning last, Local and General death,death,
1895-01-31, Wednesday, On Wednesday morning Jan 16th Mrs. <PERSON>Joseph Dowe</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Onslow</LOCATION> passed peacefully away at the age of 30 years. The Rev. Mr. <PERSON>Austin</PERSON> preached the funeral sermon after which the remains were interred in the Eardley cemetary, Local and General,death,
1895-01-31,Monday,Our heart goes forth in the deepest of sympathy to our confrere Mr. W. . Cliff editor and proprietor of the <ORGANIZATION>Carleton Place Central</ORGANIZATION> Canadian who has been called upon to sustain a great affliction in the death of his beloved wife which took place on Monday last after a short but severe illness,Local and general,death,
1895-01-31,Monday, Captain <PERSON>Mulligan</PERSON> wife and Miss <PERSON>Mulligan</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Pembroke</LOCATION> are spending a few days with their relatives here, <PERSON>Quyon</PERSON>,arrival,
1895-01-31,Monday, Dr. <PERSON>Groves</PERSON> who has been unable to attend to his professional duties on account of a very sore hand spent a few days with his brother <PERSON>Dr Groves</PERSON> of Carp Ont. and returned home on Monday much improved,<LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION>,arrival,
1895-01-31,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Mary J. Bell</PERSON> was the guest of Miss <PERSON>Bessie Rutledge</PERSON> Concession St. during carnival week.,<LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION>,departure,
1895-01-31,n/a,"There was a goodly representation of Pontiackers at the <ORGANIZATION>Ottawa Carnival</ORGANIZATION> last week, especially during the closing days of that noteworthy and remarkably successful affair",The <ORGANIZATION>Ottawa Carnival</ORGANIZATION>'s Success,event,
1895-01-31,n/a,The Misses M. and <PERSON>A. Brownlee</PERSON> have returned home from <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> afrer a few weeks' visit.,<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-31,n/a,The Rev. Mr. <PERSON>Eason</PERSON> has been holding special meetings for the last six weeks.,<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,church,
1895-01-31,n/a,Miss <PERSON>Lizzie Richardson</PERSON> who for the past six months has been living at <LOCATION>Carleton Place</LOCATION> has returned home for a few weeks' visit accompanied by Miss <PERSON>D. Hamilton.</PERSON>,<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,arrival,
1895-01-31,n/a,<ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> are very dull around here since the young men have gone to the woods. Some of the young ladies are very lonely.,<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,event,
1895-01-31,Saturday,"<PERSON>Claude McLachlin</PERSON> Esq. left for <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> last week from which port he sailed for <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> on Saturday per steamer ""Lucania"" of the Cunard Line. Mr. <PERSON>McLachlin</PERSON> goes to <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> on a business trip and expects to be gone about six weeks.",Local and general,departure,
1895-01-31,Sunday,Miss <PERSON>Mulligan</PERSON> of Pembroke Miss <PERSON>K. McLean</PERSON> of the <LOCATION>St. Lawrence Hall</LOCATION> and Mr. <PERSON>W. E. Rowan</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Arnprior</LOCATION> spent Sunday at <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> the guests of Mr. <PERSON>Dan</PERSON>. Smith.,<PERSON>Quyon</PERSON>,arrival,
1895-01-31,Sunday,Mr. <PERSON>H. J. Ferguson</PERSON> spent Sunday with his many friends in <LOCATION>Ottawa.</LOCATION>,<LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION>,departure,
1895-01-31,Sunday,Mr. <PERSON>John McAdam Contrsector</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Nova Scotia</LOCATION> spent Sunday at the <LOCATION>St. Lawrence Hall</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Quyon</LOCATION>,arrival,
1895-01-31,Thursday, ARTHUR McCONNELL Attourney at Law Main St. Hull Que will at request attend all courts in the district. All correspondence promptly answered. Will be at <LOCATION>Shawville</LOCATION> first Thursday of each month, advertisement,arrival,
1895-01-31,Thursday, At our patron meeting held at <LOCATION>Lichfield</LOCATION> on the 17th we had the pleasure of Mr. <PERSON>Craig</PERSON>'s company. His speech was listened to with much attention also that of Miss <PERSON>A. Bolam</PERSON>. At the next meeting held in No. 8 on Feb. 7th it was decidedd to have a taffy pull at the close of the meeting, Notes from <PERSON>Murrell</PERSON>'s Settlement,event,
1895-01-31,Tuesday, Another fatal case of diptheria occured in the village on Tuesday morning a little boy of Mr. <PERSON>Thomas Lewis</PERSON>' having succumbed to the disease, Local and General,death,
1895-01-31,Tuesday, There are no new cases of diptheria here consequently school will re-open on the 28th, Notes from <PERSON>Murrell</PERSON>'s Settlement,event,
1895-01-31,Wednesday,On Wednesday the 16th a large number of our most influential citizens called at the domicile of our very obliging and efficient and ever painstaking bus driver Mr. <PERSON>Wm Richardson</PERSON> and presented him with a handsomely filled purse and a suitable bag for his business as a token of their most sincere appreciation for his faithfulness and strict attention to duty, <PERSON>Quyon</PERSON>,event,
1895-01-31,Wednesday,"Mrs. <PERSON>R. Richardson</PERSON> had a sewing ""bea"" on Wednesday last. Quite a number of young ladies attended.",<PERSON>Radford</PERSON> notes,event,
1895-01-03,n/a,Miss <PERSON>J. McDowell</PERSON> contemplates a visit to friends across the <LOCATION>Ottawa</LOCATION> river shortly.,<LOCATION>Greer Mount</LOCATION> notes,departure,
1895-01-31,n/a,Mrs.Geo. <PERSON>McDermott</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Bristol</LOCATION> is visiting her sister Mrs. <PERSON>Jas</PERSON>. <PERSON>C. Williams</PERSON> of Arnprior.,Local and general,departure,
